. GOOD AFTERNOON.
WELCOME TO THE JULY 7TH 2026 REGULAR MEETING OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS .
>> MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL?
THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. SUPERVISE SIR CHAN CHAN
PRESIDENT SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN PRESENT SUPERVISOR DORSEY
DORSEY PRESENT SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER PRESENT
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD PRESENT SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN
PRESENT RANDLEMAN PRESENT SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR
PRESENTS SUPERVISOR SADR SADR PRESENT SUPERVISOR CHERYL
CHERYL NOT PRESENT SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON PRESENT
AND SUPERVISOR WANG WONG PRESENT MR. PRESIDENT DO YOU
HAVE A QUORUM? >> THANK YOU MADAM CLERK THE
SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT
WE ARE IN THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL HOMELAND OF THE ROMA.
TISHA ALONI WHO ARE THE ORIGINAL INHABITANTS OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO PENINSULA AS THE INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF THIS
LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE WITH THEIR TRADITIONS THE RAW
MATERIALS HAVE NEVER CEDED LOST NOR FORGOTTEN THEIR
RESPONSIBILITIES AS THE CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE AS
WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL
TERRITORY AS GUESTS WE RECOGNIZE THAT WE BENEFIT FROM
LIVING AND WORKING ON THEIR TRADITIONAL HOMELAND.
WE WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS,
ELDERS AND RELATIVES OF THE RAMAKRISHNA OWNING COMMUNITY
AND BY AFFIRMING THEIR SOVEREIGN RIGHTS AS FIRST
PEOPLES COLLEAGUES, WILL YOU JOIN ME IN RECITING THE PLEDGE
OF ALLEGIANCE? >> I, I PLEDGE ALLEGIANCE TO
THE FLAG OF THE UNITED STATES IN AMERICA AND TO THE REPUBLIC
FOR WHICH IT STANDS ONE NATION UNDER GOD INDIVISIBLE WITH
LIBERTY AND JUSTICE FOR ALL >> ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD I
WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE STAFF AT S.F. GOV TO YOU TV TODAY
THAT IS ESPECIALLY KALEENA MENDOZA.
THEY RECORD EACH OF OUR MEETINGS AND MAKE THE
TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE PUBLIC ONLINE.
>> MADAM CLERK, DO YOU HAVE ANY COMMUNICATIONS?
THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
WELCOMES YOU ALL TO BE HERE IN ATTENDANCE IN THE BOARD'S
LEGISLATIVE CHAMBER LOCATED WITHIN CITY HALL ROOM 250 ON
THE SECOND FLOOR. AND WHEN YOU'RE UNABLE TO BE
HERE, YOU MAY WATCH THE PROCEEDINGS.
THEY ARE AIRING LIVE ON S.F. GOP TV'S LOCAL CABLE CHANNEL
WHERE YOU CAN CATCH THE LIVE STREAM AT S.F. GOV TV.ORG.
AND AS SOME OF YOU MAY KNOW SB 707 NOW REQUIRES REMOTE PUBLIC
COMMENT AT FULL BOARD OF SUPERVISORS MEETINGS.
AS A REMINDER IT DOES NOT REQUIRE IT AT COMMITTEE
MEETINGS BUT TODAY IS THE FIRST DAY WE WELCOME OUR REMOTE
PUBLIC CALLERS BACK DURING PUBLIC COMMENT.
WE WILL PRIORITIZE THE INDIVIDUALS WHO ARE ABLE TO
JOIN US IN-PERSON HERE IN THE CHAMBER AND ONLY THEN ONCE WE
EXHAUST THE LINE WILL WE GO TO THE REMOTE CALLERS.
I WANT TO POINT OUT THAT LAST WEEK THE BOARD APPROVED
AMENDMENTS TO THE BOARD'S RULES OF ORDER TO PREPARE FOR
EQUIPMENT FAILURE OR DISORDERLY CONDUCT DURING PUBLIC COMMENT.
PUBLIC COMMENT MUST REMAIN GERMANE TO MATTERS WITHIN THE
JURISDICTION OF THE BOARD. PLEASE NOTE THAT
SELF-EXPRESSION CANNOT CONTAIN PERSONAL ATTACKS, HARASSMENT OR
DISCRIMINATORY REMARKS DIRECTED AT ANY CITY EMPLOYEE OR ANY
BOARD MEMBERS. FAILURE TO COMPLY WE WILL
IMMEDIATELY REDIRECT YOUR COMMENTS AND IF YOU CHOOSE TO
CONTINUE WE WILL TRANSITION TO THE NEXT SPEAKER AND JUST
REMEMBER TO ADDRESS YOUR COMMENTS TO THE BOARD AS A
WHOLE AND NOT TO INDIVIDUAL SUPERVISORS.
IF YOU'D LIKE TO SUBMIT PUBLIC COMMENT IN WRITING YOU MAY DO
SO BY SENDING AN EMAIL TO BOSS AT S.F. CAVALIERE OR USE THE
POSTAL SERVICE OR JUST ADDRESS THE ENVELOPE TO THE SAN
FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. THE NUMBER ONE DR. CARLTON BE
GOOD PLACE CITY HALL ROOM 244 SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA
94102. AND LASTLY, IF YOU'D LIKE TO
ASK FOR A REASONABLE ACCOMMODATION FOR A FUTURE
MEETING UNDER THE AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT OR TO
REQUEST LANGUAGE ASSISTANCE, PLEASE CONTACT THE CLERK'S
OFFICE AT LEAST TWO BUSINESS DAYS IN ADVANCE BY CALLING
41545545184. THANK YOU.
>> MEMBERS THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. LET'S GO TO APPROVAL OF OUR
MEETING MINUTES. >> APPROVAL OF THE JUNE 2ND,
2026 BOARD MEETING MINUTES CAN I HAVE A MOTION TO APPROVE THE
MINUTES AS PRESENTED MOVED BY SUPERVISOR CHEN IS THERE A
SECOND SECONDED BY FIELDER? >> MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED SUPERVISOR MELGAR
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EYES SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WONG WONG EYES
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN I SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR OF DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I AND SUPERVISOR MENDELSON HI
MENDELSON EITHER A LEBANESE WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MINUTES
WILL BE APPROVED AFTER PUBLIC COMMENT AS PRESENTED MADAM
CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR CONSENT AGENDA PLEASE CALL ITEMS ONE
THROUGH FOUR ITEMS ONE THROUGH FOUR ARE ON CONSENT.
THESE ITEMS ARE CONSIDERED ROUTINE.
IF A MEMBER OBJECTS AN ITEM MAY BE REMOVED AND CONSIDERED
SEPARATELY. >> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON
THESE ITEMS ON ITEMS ONE THROUGH FOUR SUPERVISOR MILLER
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EYES SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR WONG WONG EYES
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I AND SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN HI
MENDELSON I THERE ARE 11 EYES WITHOUT OBJECTION THESE
ORDINANCES ARE FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO
UNFINISHED BUSINESS PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER FIVE ITEM FIVE THIS
IS A CHARTER AMENDMENT TO AMEND THE CHARTER OF THE CITY
AND COUNTY TO AUTHORIZE THE ESTABLISHMENT OF A MUNICIPAL
FINANCE CORPORATION AND PUBLIC BANK AS NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS
AND TO SET FORTH THE MISSION PRINCIPLES AND GOVERNANCE
STRUCTURE OF THOSE CORPORATIONS AT AN ELECTION TO BE HELD ON
NOVEMBER 3RD, 2026. >> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THIS
ITEM ON ITEM FIVE SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR
SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL NO SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON
EYES SUPERVISOR WONG WONG NO SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
AND SUPERVISOR MENDELSON HI MENDELSON I THERE ARE NINE EYES
AND TWO NOSE WITH SUPERVISORS CHERYL AND WONG VOTING NO THE
CHARTER AMENDMENT IS ORDERED SUBMITTED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO
TO NEW BUSINESS PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER SIX ITEM SIX THIS
IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE PLANNING CODE TO PRINCIPALLY
PERMIT THE RELOCATION OF BAR USES WITH ALCOHOL BEVERAGE
CONTROL LICENSE AS OF MAY 19TH 2003 WITHIN THE THIRD STREET
ALCOHOL RESTRICTED USE DISTRICT AND THE BAYVIEW NEIGHBORHOOD
COMMERCIAL DISTRICT TO ALLOW ESTABLISHMENTS WITH ALCOHOL
BEVERAGE CONTROL LICENSEES AS OF MAY 19TH, 2003 AND TO
REESTABLISH THE USE UNDER THE EXISTING LICENSE WITHIN THE RFD
AND THE NCD TO AFFIRM THE SECRET DETERMINATION AND TO
MAKE THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS, PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM
SIX SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR EYES SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
SUPERVISOR ONE WONG I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHAN I
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
AND SUPERVISOR MENDELSON RANDLEMAN EITHER ARE LEBANESE
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER SEVEN ITEM SEVEN THIS IS
AN ORDINANCE TO WAIVE THE STREET ENCROACHMENT PERMIT FEE
AND ANNUAL PUBLIC RIGHT OF WAY OCCUPANCY FEE FOR A PROJECT
SPONSOR TO INSTALL AND MAINTAIN A WASTE BIN ENCLOSURE ON THE
SIDEWALK ADJACENT TO THE HARRY ST STEPS AT THE INTERSECTION OF
LAIDLEY AND HARRY STREETS IN THE UPPER SNOWY AND DIAMOND
HEIGHTS NEIGHBORHOOD AND TO AFFIRM THE SEQUEL DETERMINATION
. >> OH LET'S TAKE THIS ITEM SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS
PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM EIGHT
ITEM EIGHT WAS REFERRED WITHOUT RECOMMENDATION FROM THE LAND
USE AND TRANSPORTATION COMMITTEE.
ITEM EIGHT IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE HEALTH PLANNING
POLICE AND BUSINESS AND TAX REGULATIONS CODES TO ESTABLISH
A NEW PERMIT TYPE FOR CANNABIS CAFES TO BE ADMINISTERED BY THE
OFFICE OF CANNABIS THAT WILL AUTHORIZE THE COMMITTEE TO SELL
CANNABIS AND CANNABIS PRODUCTS ONLY FOR CONSUMPTION ON THE
PREMISES OF THE CAFE AND TO AFFIRM THE SECOND DETERMINATION
AND TO MAKE THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
>> CHAIR MELGAR, THANK YOU SO MUCH PRESIDENT AND THANK YOU
FOR YOUR SPONSORSHIP OF THIS ITEM.
THIS CAME OUT OF THE LAND USE AND TRANSPORTATION COMMITTEE
WITHOUT RECOMMENDATION SO THAT WE COULD VOTE ON IT AND THE
FULL BOARD AND I WOULD HAVE VOTED AGAINST IT DESPITE HAVING
BEEN A VERY STRONG SUPPORTER OF THE CANNABIS INDUSTRY
THROUGHOUT MY TIME ON THE PLANNING COMMISSION AND HERE ON
THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS I FEEL LIKE WE NEED TO DO MORE TO
SUPPORT THE INDUSTRY THE BRICK AND MORTAR RETAILERS WHO HAVE
NOT SEEN WHAT WE SORT OF SOLD TO THEM PROMISED THEM WHEN WE
FIRST PERMITTED RETAIL SALE OF CANNABIS MOVING FROM MEDICINAL
ONLY. HOWEVER, WHAT I DON'T LIKE
ABOUT THIS LEGISLATION IS THAT IT PERMITS ENDORSE SMOKING
AND I THINK THAT IS GOING BACKWARD ON OUR PUBLIC HEALTH
GOALS. I KNOW MANY OF US, YOU KNOW,
SEE THIS THIS ISSUE DIFFERENTLY .
I WAS AT THE JAMESTOWN COMMUNITY CENTER BEFORE WE I
BECAME SUPERVISOR AND DURING THOSE DAYS WAS WHEN JOEL WAS
SORT OF FORMING AS A CORPORATION HERE IN OUR CITY
AND ALL OF A SUDDEN WE WERE CONFISCATING THESE LITTLE US
WHAT LOOKED LIKE LITTLE USB DEVICES FROM MIDDLE SCHOOLERS
AND WE SAW A RISE IN NICOTINE USE AND NICOTINE ADDICTION
AMONG MIDDLE SCHOOLERS AND HERE WE ARE TEN YEARS LATER LOOKING
AT AN ENTIRE GENERATION IN SAN FRANCISCO GEN Z THAT HAS SEEN
SMOKING RATES GO UP. SO I FEEL LIKE WE NEED TO BE
LOOKING AT THIS WHOLE THING DIFFERENTLY.
I THINK THAT INDOOR SMOKE WHETHER IT'S CANNABIS OR
TOBACCO IS A SERIOUS PUBLIC HEALTH ISSUE.
I DON'T THINK THAT BECAUSE YOU KNOW THE TOLERANCE CHANGES THAT
YOU KNOW, WE SHOULD BE GOING BACKWARDS ON OUR PUBLIC HEALTH
GOALS AND YOU KNOW, EVEN THOUGH I WELCOME BEING ABLE TO SERVE
FOOD AND CANNABIS INFUSED PRODUCTS WHETHER THEY'RE DRINKS
OR FOOD AND THE CREATIVITY THAT THAT WILL BRING, I WELCOME
THAT. I THINK IT'S GOOD I CANNOT
SUPPORT GOING BACKWARDS ON OUR INDOOR SMOKING GOALS.
>> SO WITH THAT WITH ALL DUE RESPECT TO PRESIDENT MANDELL
AND THANK YOU FOR HELPING THE INDUSTRY AND FOR PUTTING THIS
FORWARD BUT I CANNOT SUPPORT IT.
>> THANKS MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM EIGHT
SUPERVISOR MELGAR NO MELGAR NO SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EYES
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON EYES
SUPERVISOR WONG WONG NO SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN NO
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN NO SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
AND SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI MENDELSON I THERE ARE SEVEN
EYES AND FOUR NOS WITH SUPERVISORS MELGAR WONG CHAN
AND CHIN VOTING NO AND THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST
READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL AT A NUMBER NINE ITEM NINE THIS
IS A CHARTER AMENDMENT TO AMEND THE CHARTER OF THE CITY
AND COUNTY BY REQUIRING OR AUTHORIZING THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS TO AMEND SPECIFIED INITIATIVE ORDINANCES TRANSFER
FROM THE CHARTER TO THE MUNICIPAL CODE CERTAIN
COMMISSIONS AND ADVISORY BODIES IN SOME CASES WITH MODIFIED
FUNCTIONS AND OTHER VARIOUS CHANGES.
AND MR. PRESIDENT, I WILL ADD THAT PURSUANT TO BOARD RULE
2.22.7 AT LEAST SIX DAYS MUST INTERVENE BETWEEN THE FIRST
APPEARANCE OF A PROPOSED CHARTER AMENDMENT WHICH IS WHY
THE QUESTION AS YOU CAN SEE IS STATED SHALL THIS CHARTER
AMENDMENT BE CONTINUED? >> AND THANK YOU FOR MAKING
THAT POINT MADAM CLERK. IT IS A GOOD THING TO KEEP
IN MIND THAT WITH THESE MEASURES THE FIRST VOTE IS
USUALLY SIMPLY ON A CONTINUANCE AND NORMALLY JUST A THING THAT
EVERYBODY VOTES FOR. >> SO MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU
PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM NINE ON ITEM NINE.
>> SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SAUTER.
SAUTER I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON
WALTON I SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
AND SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN II MANDOLIN I THERE ARE 11 EYES
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE CHARTER AMENDMENT IS CONTINUED TO JULY
14TH 2026 MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER TEN ITEM TEN
THIS IS A CHARTER AMENDMENT TO AMEND THE CHARTER OF THE CITY
AND COUNTY TO INCREASE THE AMOUNT OF FUNDING THE CITY MUST
APPROPRIATE TO THE HOUSING TRUST FUND EACH FISCAL YEAR
THAT IS USED FOR THE CREATION ACQUISITION AND REHABILITATION
OF AFFORDABLE RENTAL AND OWNERSHIP HOUSING FOR DOWN
PAYMENT LOANS AND HOUSING STABILIZATION FOR CERTAIN
HOUSEHOLDS AND FOR HOUSING RELATED INFRASTRUCTURE TO
PROVIDE FOR A TEMPORARY FREEZE AND TEMPORARY REDUCTION IN THE
ANNUAL APPROPRIATE RETURN TO THE HOUSING TRUST FUND UNDER
CERTAIN CIRCUMSTANCES TO EXTEND THE SUNSET DATE OF THE HOUSING
TRUST FUND FROM JULY 1ST, 2043 TO JULY 1ST, 2058 AND TO DELETE
OBSOLETE ABSOLUTE OBSOLETE PROVISIONS AT AN ELECTION TO BE
HELD ON NOVEMBER 3RD, 2026. THE QUESTION HERE, MR.
PRESIDENT, IS CONTROLLED BY THE SAME BOARD RULE SO THE CHARTER
AMENDMENT BE CONTINUED. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
SUPERVISOR CHEN THANK YOU FOR PRESENT.
I KNOW WE KNOW THAT PASSAGE PERSIST IN HOUSING AND SECURITY
CONTINUE TO PUSH OUT MANY OF OUR WORKING FAMILIES,
VULNERABLE COMMUNITIES AND OUR LOCAL WORKERS AND YET OUR LOCAL
AFFORDABLE HOUSING FUNDING SOURCES ARE RUNNING DRIVE.
EARLIER THIS YEAR I ASKED TO BE ABLE TO CONDUCT AN INDEPENDENT
ANALYSIS TO IDENTIFY FUNDING AND FUND FINANCING MECHANISMS
FOR AFFORDABLE HOUSING. THIS AFFORDABLE HOUSING TRUST
FUND IS ONE OF THOSE STRATEGY THAT IS NEEDED IN ORDER TO
BRING OUR AFFORDABLE HOUSING PRODUCTION TO SCALE IN COMING
YEARS AS WELL AS MY CHARTER AMENDMENT TO ESTABLISH A
MUNICIPAL FINANCIAL CORPORATION AND PUBLIC BANK AND OTHER
STRATEGY TO EVENTS, SOCIAL HOUSING MODELS AND FINANCING
TOOLS. I WANT TO APPRECIATE THE
LEADERSHIP OF SUPERVISOR MELGAR AND THE MAYOR'S OFFICE AND MANY
ADVOCATES AND PARTNERS THAT HAVE CRAFTED THIS AFFORDABLE
HOUSING TRUST FUND CHARTER AMENDMENT AND PLEASED AT ME AS
THE CO-SPONSOR FOR THIS THANK YOU CHAIR WALTON THANK YOU SO
MUCH PRESIDENT MADAM AND I KNOW YOU DO SEE MY NAME LISTED AS A
CO-SPONSOR AND I DO WANT TO SAY I'M GOING TO SUPPORT THIS THIS
AFTERNOON BUT I DO THINK THAT IT'S ARBITRARY TO SUPPORT THIS
LEGISLATION TO SUPPORT MORE RESOURCES GOING TO THE HOUSING
TRUST FUND AND THEN TURN AROUND AND SUPPORT REDUCING THE AMOUNT
OF AFFORDABLE HOUSING. I MEAN IT JUST DOESN'T MAKE
SENSE. SO I CAN SAY THAT I SUPPORT
THIS TODAY BUT I CANNOT SAY THAT I WON'T ADVOCATE AGAINST
THIS IN THE NEXT COUPLE OF WEEKS AS WE MOVE FORWARD.
THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. THANK YOU, CHAIR WALTON UNLESS
SOMEONE NEEDS A ROLL CALL WHICH I DON'T THINK ANYBODY DOES ON
THE CONTINUANCE, WE CAN TAKE THE CONTINUANCE.
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE CHARTER
AMENDMENT IS CONTINUED TO JULY 14TH, 2026.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 11.
ITEM 11 THIS IS A MOTION TO APPOINT MICHAEL CHUNG RESIDENCY
REQUIREMENT WAIVED TERM ENDING JANUARY 15TH 2029 AND TANGERINE
BRIGHAM RESIDENCY REQUIREMENT WAIVE TERM ENDING JANUARY 15TH
2027 TO THE SAN FRANCISCO HEALTH AUTHORITY.
>> LET'S TAKE THAT ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE MOTION IS APPROVED AND LET'S GO TO OUR
COMMITTEE REPORTS. >> YES ITEMS 12, 13 AND 15 WERE
CONSIDERED BY THE RULES COMMITTEE AT A REGULAR MEETING
ON MONDAY JULY 6TH, 2026 AND WE'RE RECOMMENDED AS
AMENDED WITH NEW TITLES AS COMMITTEE REPORTS ITEM 12 THIS
IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO CREATE
THE CHESTNUT STREET ENTERTAINMENT ZONE ON CHESTNUT
STREET FROM DIVISION ADERO TO FILLMORE STREET STEINER STREET
FROM CHESTNUT TO LOMBARD STREETS, PIERCE STREET FROM
CHESTNUT TO LOMBARD STREET AND SCOTT STREET FROM CHESTNUT
TO LOMBARD STREET THE NEW SECTION IS AND TO UPDATE
CROSS-REFERENCES TO THE TRANSPORTATION CODE AND TO
AFFIRM THE SEQUENT DETERMINATION LET'S TAKE THIS
ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE
IS PASSED ON FIRST READING AND ITEM 14 WAS NOT REFERRED TO
THE FULL BOARD MADAM CLERK SO PLEASE CALL ITEMS 13 AND 15
TOGETHER ITEM 13 THIS IS A MOTION TO WHICH NOW READS TO
APPROVE THE MAYOR'S NOMINATION FOR APPOINTMENT OF RIDGELEY TO
THE PORT COMMISSION TERM ENDING MAY 1ST 2030.
THE WORD REJECTING WAS STRUCK AS WELL ON ITEM 15 THE MOTION
NOW READS MOTION TO APPROVE THE MAYOR'S NOMINATION FOR
REAPPOINTMENT OF WILLIAM ADAMS TO THE PORT COMMISSION TERM
ENDING MAY FIRST 2030 AND WE COULD TAKE THAT SAME HOUSE SAME
CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTIONS ARE APPROVED AND MADAM
CLERK LET'S GO TO ROLL CALL FOR INTRODUCTIONS.
>> YES SUPERVISOR MALE GARS FIRST UP TO INTRODUCE NEW
BUSINESS SUBMIT SUBMIT THANK YOU.
>> SUPERVISOR SUPERVISOR SAUTER THANK YOU MADAM CLERK
COLLEAGUES TODAY I AM SUBMITTING A LETTER OF INQUIRY
TO THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WORKS TO BETTER ANSWER HOW THE
CITY MAINTAINS ITS SIDEWALKS AND CURB RAMPS.
SIDEWALKS ARE ONE OF OUR CITY'S MOST BASIC AND CORE PIECES OF
INFRASTRUCTURE. >> WE ALL USE THEM AND WE ALL
EXPECT THEM TO BE IN GOOD SHAPE WHEN A SIDEWALK IS BUCKLED OR
CORNER HAS NO CURB RAMP IT CAN BE MORE THAN A SLIGHT
INCONVENIENCE. IT CAN BE A SIGN OF BROKEN
TRUST FROM RESIDENTS WHO EXPECT US TO DO THE SMALL THINGS RIGHT
. IT CAN BE A MAJOR BARRIER TO
NEIGHBORS WITH MOBILITY CHALLENGES WHO NEED TO
CAREFULLY PLAN OUT THEIR ROUTES AND AS ARE SIGNIFICANT RECORD
OF SETTLEMENTS FOR SIDEWALK CONDITION SHOW IT CAN BE A
COSTLY LIABILITY TO THE CITY AS WELL.
>> I FREQUENTLY HEAR FROM CONSTITUENTS WHO HAVE REQUESTED
SIDEWALK REPAIRS ON THEIR BLOCK AND HAVE LITTLE IDEA OF WHEN OR
IF THESE REPAIRS WILL TAKE PLACE.
MANY HAVE BEEN ASKING AND WONDERING FOR YEARS
AND SADLY MANY HAVE STORIES OF NEARBY NEIGHBORS OR FRIENDS WHO
WERE THEMSELVES INJURED BY THE HAZARDOUS CONDITIONS THEY
OBSERVED. SO WHEN A CONSTITUENT ASKED ME
A SIMPLE QUESTION SUCH AS WHEN WILL THE SIDEWALK BE FIXED, I
WANT TO BE ABLE TO GIVE THEM A STRAIGHT ANSWER.
I CAN'T DO THAT TODAY WHICH IS WHY I'M ASKING PUBLIC WORKS TO
ANSWER FUNDAMENTAL QUESTIONS ABOUT THEIR CURB RAMP
AND SIDEWALK REPAIR PROGRAM. OUR LETTER OF INQUIRY WILL ASK
A NUMBER OF QUESTIONS FOR EXAMPLE HOW MANY SIDEWALK
CORNERS CURRENTLY DO NOT HAVE A CURB RAMP AND WHAT IS THE
AVERAGE TIME BETWEEN A REQUEST BEING MADE AND A SIDEWALK
REPAIR BEING COMPLETED? WHAT ARE THE CHANGES THAT
PUBLIC WORKS IS CONSIDERING TO IMPROVE THE SPEED AND REDUCE
THE COST OF SIDEWALK REPAIRS AND HOW MUCH HAS THE CITY PAID
OUT IN SETTLEMENTS RELATED TO SIDEWALK CONDITIONS OVER THE
PAST TEN YEARS? WE NEED TO MAKE SURE THAT EVERY
STEP IN THIS PROCESS FROM RESIDENTS CONCERNED ABOUT A
SIDEWALK TO PUBLIC WORKS EMPLOYEES POURING CONCRETE IS
SET UP SET UP FOR SUCCESS AND RESULTS IN SMOOTHER, MORE
ACCESSIBLE SIDEWALKS FOR ALL OF US TO NAVIGATE.
THAT'S MY GOAL AND THAT IS WHAT THIS LETTER OF INQUIRY WILL
WORK TOWARDS THAN THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR SAUTER SUPERVISOR CHERYL SUBMIT THANK
YOU. SUPERVISOR WALTON WE SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR WONG SUBMIT THANK YOU SUPERVISOR
CHAN THANK YOU MADAM CLERK COLLEAGUES THE FIRST RESOLUTION
I'M INTRODUCING TODAY URGES THE NATIONAL ARCHIVES AND RECORDS
ADMINISTRATION TO HALT THE CLOSURE OF THE NATIONAL ARCHIVE
AT SAN FRANCISCO AND LOCATE AND RELOCATION OF THE
FACILITY'S RECORDS AND ARTIFACTS THE NATIONAL
ARCHIVES AND RECORDS ADMINISTRATION IS THE NATION'S
OFFICIAL RECORD KEEPER TASKED TO SAFEGUARD AND PROVIDE PUBLIC
ACCESS TO ESSENTIAL LEGAL AND HISTORIC AND HISTORICAL
DOCUMENTS THAT TELL THE COMPLETE STORY AND HISTORY OF
THE UNITED STATES AND ITS PEOPLE AND NARA'S REGIONAL
ARCHIVES WERE CREATED TO ENSURE THAT RECORDS CREATED BY FEDERAL
AGENCIES ACROSS THE COUNTRY REMAIN IN THE REGION IN WHICH
THEY WERE CREATED ENSURING THAT THE PUBLIC HAS ACCESS TO
FEDERAL RECORDS CREATED IN THEIR OWN COMMUNITIES.
THE SAN FRANCISCO AREA FACILITY HOLDS MORE THAN 75,000 CUBIC
FEET OF VALUABLE HISTORICAL RECORDS DATING BACK TO THE
1850S AND SERVES AS THE RECORD KEEPING FOR THE WEST COAST
REGION INCLUDING NORTON IN CENTRAL CALIFORNIA, NEVADA,
HAWAII, AMERICAN SAMOA, GUAM AND TERRITORIES IN THE PACIFIC
ISLANDS MOST NOTABLY THE NATIONAL ARCHIVE AS SAN
FRANCISCO IS HOME TO THE WORLD'S MOST COMPREHENSIVE
COLLECTION OF RECORDS DETAILING THE ASIAN AMERICAN EXPERIENCE
INCLUDING HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS OF FILES FROM THE CHINESE
EXCLUSION ACT, WORLD WAR TWO INCARCERATION OF JAPANESE
AND JAPANESE-AMERICAN INS AND ARRIVAL RECORDS FROM THE
ANGEL ISLAND IMMIGRATION STATION.
IT ALSO HOLDS ORIGINAL CASE FILES OF LANDMARK CIVIL RIGHTS
VICTORIES INCLUDING UNITED STATES VERSUS WONG KIM ARK, THE
1898 SUPREME COURT DECISION THAT ESTABLISHED BIRTHRIGHT
CITIZENSHIP UNDER THE 14TH AMENDMENT WHICH WAS AFFIRMED
AND REAFFIRMED BY LAST WEEK'S SUPREME COURT RULING IN JUNE
AND HRA ANNOUNCED PLANS TO CLOSE THE NATIONAL ARCHIVES AS
SAN FRANCISCO AND RELOCATE ALL RECORDS AND ARTIFACTS TO OTHER
FACILITIES ACROSS THE COUNTRY. THIS CREATES A VERY DIFFICULT
AND SIGNIFICANT BARRIER FOR COMMUNITIES TO ACCESS THEIR
RECORDS EFFECTIVELY SILENCING OUR VOICES AND EXPERIENCES WE
MUST ENSURE THAT OUR LOCAL COMMUNITIES CONTINUE TO HAVE
DIRECT PHYSICAL ACCESS TO PUBLIC EVIDENCE, PUBLIC RECORD
OF OUR HISTORY AND STORIES IN THIS COUNTRY AND COLLEAGUES.
ANOTHER AND THE SECOND RESOLUTION I AM INTRODUCING
TODAY IS TO A RESOLUTION URGES SUPPORT FOR CALIFORNIA ASSEMBLY
BILL 1448 AUTHORED BY ASSEMBLY MEMBER GREG HART WHICH AMENDS
THE CALIFORNIA COASTAL PROTECTION ACT AND EXPLICITLY
CLOSES THE LOOPHOLE THAT ALLOWS EXPANSION OF OFFSHORE OFFSHORE
OIL DRILLING. CALIFORNIA'S ICONIC COASTLINE
IS A VITAL ENVIRONMENTAL, ECOLOGICAL AND ECONOMIC ASSET
THAT CONTRIBUTES OVER $44 BILLION ANNUALLY TO THE STATES
AND SUPPORTS MORE THAN 500,000 JOBS IN TOURISM RECREATION
AND COMMERCIAL FISHING. BUT WE HAVE ALSO SUFFERED
SEVERE ENVIRONMENTAL AND ECONOMIC DEVASTATION DUE TO
OFFSHORE OIL SPILLS THAT HAS DESTROYED MARINE HABITAT
AND SHATTER LOCAL COASTAL ECONOMICS.
>> THE FEDERAL ADMINISTRATION RECENTLY PROPOSED EXPANSION OF
OFFSHORE OIL AND GAS DRILLING LEASES WITHIN FEDERAL WATERS
OFF THE PACIFIC COAST WHICH THREATENS TO REVERSE DECADES OF
BIPARTISAN COASTAL PROTECTIONS .
IT INCREASES THE RISK OF FUTURE DISASTERS AB 1448 WILL PROHIBIT
THE STATE LANDS COMMISSION FROM APPROVING EXPANSION OF DRILLING
FACILITIES WHILE TIGHTENING RULES ON RENEWAL MODIFICATION
AND TRANSFER OF EXISTING LEASES.
THE CALIFORNIA COASTAL PROTECTION ACT IS ESSENTIAL TO
PRESERVE THE STATE'S COASTLINE, SAFEGUARD OUR ECONOMY, PROTECT
MARINE ENVIRONMENT AND PUBLIC HEALTH AND ADVANCE CALIFORNIA'S
CLIMATE RESILIENCE GOALS AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHAN
SUPERVISOR CHEN SUBMIT. THANK YOU SUPER VISOR DORSEY
SUBMIT THANK YOU. AND SUPERVISOR FIELDER SUBMIT
THANK YOU SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD SHOULD WE GO OR SHOULD WE?
>> WE CAN GET THROUGH MAHMUD IN THE ROLL BIN WILL GO TAKE IT
AWAY THANK YOU COLLEAGUES. THANK YOU, PRESIDENT I HAVE A
COUPLE OF ITEMS I'M INTRODUCING TODAY.
>> FIRST I AM CALLING FOR A HEARING LOOKING INTO TWO CASES
OF MASS EVICTIONS AND PROPERTY MISMANAGEMENT BY THE DOBYNS
MANAGEMENT COMPANY AND THE MISTREATMENT OF ITS RESIDENTS
AT TWO PROPERTIES THEY MANAGE IN THE WESTERN CONDITION MLK
MARCUS GARVEY SQUARE CO-OP AND THOMAS PAINE SQUARE
APARTMENTS. WHILE THE PARTICULARS OF THE
EVENTS ARE AT, THE TWO COMPLEXES ARE DISTINCT THERE
ARE PATTERNS DEMONSTRATED THAT NEED TO BE BROUGHT TO BROADER
ATTENTION SCRUTINY SO THESE PATTERNS ARE NOT REPEATED
ELSEWHERE. RESIDENTS AT BOTH COMPLEXES
HAVE BEEN FRUSTRATED WITH PROPERTY MANAGEMENT AND THE
OVERSIGHT OF THESE PROPERTIES AND HAVE COME TO US TO SEEK
ANSWERS IN A WAY FORWARD. >> LAST YEAR AROUND CHRISTMAS
MULTIPLE TENANTS AT THOMAS PAINE SQUARE REPORTED THAT
PEOPLE THAT THEY HAD IDENTIFIED AS MANAGEMENT STAFF ACCESS
THEIR UNITS AND ALLEGEDLY REMOVED GIFTS AND OTHER
PROPERTIES. DOORBELL CAMERA FOOTAGE CAUGHT
THE INCIDENTS LIVE. BUT THIS GOES BACK EVEN
FURTHER. IN FACT, ON THE VERY FIRST DAY
I WAS SWORN INTO OFFICE WE BEGAN RECEIVING DAILY PHONE
CALLS FROM A DISABLED AND SENIOR RESIDENT WHO WAS
EFFECTIVELY TRAPPED ON THE SECOND FLOOR AT THOMAS PAINE.
THAT SAME WEEK TWO MORE SENIORS REPORTED REPEATED DELAYS
IN ADDRESSING ACCESSIBILITY RELATED MAINTENANCE REQUESTS.
IT BECAME CLEAR THAT FIRST WEEK THAT THE RESIDENTS AT THOMAS
PAINE HAVE BEEN IGNORED FOR YEARS.
WE ALSO CONTINUE TO HEAR FROM RESIDENTS AT THE BOARD WHEN
RESIDENTS CAME TO PUBLIC COMMENT LAST YEAR.
THIS INCLUDES RESIDENTS CLAIMING FALSE EVICTION NOTICES
,NOT ACCEPTING RENT PAYMENT AND A LONG LIST OF BUILDING
SAFETY ISSUES INCLUDING MOLD AND ASBESTOS ISSUES AS WELL.
>> RESIDENT COUNCIL LEADERSHIP THAT WE HAVE MET WITH ALSO
REPORTED HARASSMENT FROM BUILDING MANAGEMENT
AND SECURITY AND NOTED THAT SECURITY GUARDS HAVE NOT DONE
ENOUGH TO KEEP RESIDENTS SAFE ESPECIALLY AS A RESIDENT WAS
BEATEN WITH A HAMMER EARLIER THIS YEAR.
>> OUR OFFICE HEARD FIRSTHAND ABOUT THE UNSECURED ENTRANCES
INADEQUATE SECURITY STAFFING AND DELAYED RESPONSES TO SAFETY
INCIDENTS THAT LEFT MANY FEELING UNSAFE EVEN IN THEIR
OWN HOMES. >> RESIDENTS HAVE ALSO REPORTED
LONG STANDING ISSUES WITH DOMA'S HANDLING OF THE
RECERTIFICATION PROCESS WHICH IS NECESSARY FOR KEEPING THOSE
AND AFFORDABLE HOUSING VOUCHERS IN THEIR HOMES.
>> THIS HAS BEEN A PROBLEM AT BOTH THOMAS PAINE AND AT MLK
MARCUS GARVEY CO-OP. >> DESPITE THESE ALLEGED
ISSUES, DOMAS AND THE MARCUS GARVEY BOARD HAVE MOVED FORWARD
WITH EVICTION PROCEEDINGS FOR OVER A DOZEN CO-OP RESIDENTS.
MANY OF WHOM HAVE LIVED THERE FOR DECADES.
>> TENANT RIGHTS GROUPS WE ARE COLLABORATING WITH HAVE NOTED
HOW UNUSUALLY FAST AND AGGRESSIVE THIS EVICTION
PROCESS HAS BEEN. MLK MARCUS GARVEY HAS ALSO BEEN
THE SITE OF SEVERAL DB COMPLAINTS ABOUT ROOFS CAVING
IN MOLD AND OTHER SERIOUS WATER AND SEWER ISSUES THAT IMPACT
THE LIVABILITY OF THE UNITS AT THE CO-OP ESPECIALLY FOR THE
MANY SENIORS THAT CALL THE COMPLEX HOME.
IN ADDITION TO DOMAS WE WILL BE ALSO INVITING LEADERSHIP FROM
MLK, MARCUS GARVEY CO-OP BOARD AND REPRESENTATIVES FROM BETHEL
AME CHURCH WHO OWN THOMAS PAINE SQUARE APARTMENTS AS WELL AS
REPRESENTATIVES FROM HUD AND THE HUMAN RIGHTS
COMMISSION. WE ARE HOPING FOR PRODUCTIVE
CONVERSATIONS THAT NOT ONLY DRIVE SOLUTIONS FOR RESIDENTS
AT THESE COMPLEXES BUT SET A STANDARD FOR PROPERTY
MANAGEMENT ACROSS THE CITY. I WANT TO THANK THE HOUSING
RIGHTS COMMITTEE EVICTION DEFENSE COLLABORATIVE OPENDOOR
LEGAL, MLK, MARCUS GARVEY SHAREHOLDERS AND THOMAS PAINE
SQUARE APARTMENTS TENANTS FOR BRINGING THESE ONGOING ISSUES
TO OUR OFFICERS ATTENTION AND COLLABORATING ON FINDING
SOLUTIONS TO ONGOING RESIDENT ISSUES.
>> I PLAN TO HOLD THE HEARING AT SOME POINT IN THE FALL AT
THE GOVERNMENT AUDIT AND OVERSIGHT COMMITTEE NEXT
I'M INTRODUCING AN UPDATE TO THE PLANNING CODE THAT WILL
MAKE IT EASIER FOR HOUSING PROJECTS TO MEET CODE
REQUIREMENTS WHILE STILL PROVIDING VALUABLE ROOFTOP OPEN
SPACE. EARLIER THIS YEAR THE
DEPARTMENT OF BUILDING INSPECTION BEGAN MORE STRICTLY
ENFORCING A LONGSTANDING PLUMBING CODE REQUIREMENT THAT
COMMON USE AREAS INCLUDING THOSE ON ROOFTOPS MUST HAVE AN
ADJACENT RESTROOM FOR USE BY RESIDENTS AND THEIR GUESTS.
>> TELLING RESIDENTS TO HOLD IT FOR AN ELEVATOR RIDE TO THE
LOBBY WASN'T GOING TO CUT IT APPARENTLY BECAUSE OF THIS AT
LEAST TWO PROJECTS IN THE CITY INCLUDING THE FREEDOM WEST
SENIOR APARTMENTS IN DISTRICT FIVE HAVE ARE COMING OR HAVING
TO COME UP WITH NEW DESIGNS TO ACCOMMODATE THE REQUIREMENT
BECAUSE OF HEIGHT LIMITS. THE CHANGES WILL LIKELY MEAN
FINDING SPACE ON THE TOP OCCUPIED FLOOR THAT WOULD HAVE
LIKELY HAD A BETTER USE AND KEPT FLOOR DESIGNS UNIFORM
. IT COULD ALSO HAVE REQUIRED
MAKING THE TRADEOFF BETWEEN BUILDING AFFORDABLE HOUSING OR
HAVING A HIGHER HEIGHT LIMIT TO ACCOMMODATE THIS EXTRA
BATHROOM. BUT WITH THE LEGISLATION I'M
INTRODUCING TODAY THERE'LL BE ANOTHER OPTION.
UNDER THIS ORDINANCE PROJECTS ARE ALLOWED TO ADD A RESTROOM
TO THEIR ROOF WITHOUT IT COUNTING AGAINST THE BUILDING'S
HEIGHT LIMIT SO LONG AS THAT RESTROOM SERVES A COMMON SPACE
AND IT TAKES UP LESS THAN 30% OF THE AREA ON THE ROOF.
>> THIS MEANS THE PROJECTS THAT OTHERWISE WOULD HAVE HAD TO
EITHER CARVE OUT SPACE ON THEIR TOP FLOOR FOR A BATHROOM ADDING
COMPLEXITY AND PERHAPS EVEN SHRINKING FLOOR PLANS OR FORGO
A ROOFTOP COMMONS SPACE ENTIRELY CAN NOW MEET
REQUIREMENTS BY ADDING A RESTROOM TO THE ROOF WITHOUT
WORRYING ABOUT HEIGHT LIMITS. I LIKE TO THANK DEPUTY CITY
ATTORNEY ROB COPPOLA, MY LEGISLATIVE AIDE RANDALL COOPER
AND LISA GLUCKSTEIN FOR THEIR WORK ON THIS ITEM.
I ASK FOR YOUR SUPPORT COLLEAGUES TO BRING RELIEF TO
FUTURE RESIDENTS. ROOFTOP REVELERS EVERYWHERE.
>> LASTLY, SPEAKING OF REVELRY, I WANT TO THANK ALL OF OUR CITY
EMPLOYEES, FIRST RESPONDERS, TRANSIT OPERATORS AND EVENT
STAFF WHO WORKED OVER THE 4TH OF JULY WEEKEND UNDER
CHALLENGING CONDITIONS. >> SAN FRANCISCO HOSTED A
HISTORIC CELEBRATION FOR THE NATION'S 250TH ANNIVERSARY
AND THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE CAME TO ENJOY IT.
>> WE WANT THESE EVENTS TO BE SUCCESSFUL, SAFE AND ACCESSIBLE
. >> UNFORTUNATELY FOR MANY
RESIDENTS AND VISITORS, THE EVENING BECAME DEFINED BY
SEVERE TRANSPORTATION GRIDLOCK THAT AFFECTED BUSSES, EMERGENCY
ACCESS, RIDESHARE SERVICES, PRIVATE VEHICLES, AUTONOMOUS
VEHICLES AND SIMPLY TRYING TO GET HOME.
>> THAT IS WHY TODAY I AM SUBMITTING A LETTER OF INQUIRY
TO THE MAYOR'S OFFICE OF MTA AND THE DEPARTMENT EMERGENCY
MANAGEMENT AND THE FIRE DEPARTMENT TO LEARN ABOUT WHAT
WENT WRONG ON OUR STREETS. THIS LETTER IS NOT ABOUT
ASSIGNING BLAME. IT'S ABOUT UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAPPENED, WHAT WORKED AND WHAT DID NOT AND HOW WE IMPROVE
BEFORE THE NEXT MAJOR EVENT. WE KNOW AGENCIES INVESTED
SIGNIFICANT TIME IN PLANNING. THE QUESTION IS WHETHER THE
OPERATIONAL PLANS MATCH THE REALITY OF TURNOUT AND TRAVEL
PATTERNS. WE'RE PARTICULARLY INTERESTED
IN HOW CITY DEPARTMENTS IN THE MAYOR'S OFFICE COORDINATED ONE
ANOTHER WITH THE PRESIDIO AND WITH PRIVATE TRANSPORTATION
PROVIDERS BEFORE AND DURING THE EVENT.
>> THE ROLE OF AUTONOMOUS VEHICLES DESERVES PARTICULAR
ATTENTION AS WELL. >> RESIDENTS SAW REPORTS
AND IMAGES OF STALLED OR IMMOBILIZED VEHICLES
CONTRIBUTING TO CONGESTION AND WE NEED A CLEAR
UNDERSTANDING OF WHAT OCCURRED. >> EARLIER THIS YEAR WE AT THE
BOARD HELD A HEARING ON AUTONOMOUS VEHICLE PERFORMANCE
DURING THE DECEMBER 2025 POWER OUTAGE.
>> THIS PAST FOURTH OF JULY RAISES ADDITIONAL QUESTIONS
ABOUT HOW THESE VEHICLES OPERATE DURING LARGE SCALE
EVENTS AND UNUSUAL TRAFFIC CONDITIONS AND CONTRIBUTE TO
THE DEGRADATION OF THE NETWORK ON THE WHOLE.
WE ALSO WANT TO UNDERSTAND HOW EMERGENCY RESPONDERS WERE
AFFECTED IN A CITYWIDE CONGESTION EVENT MAINTAINING
ACCESS FOR FIRE, EMS AND PUBLIC SAFETY RESOURCES MUST REMAIN
THE HIGHEST PRIORITY. THIS REVIEW SHOULD ALSO EXAMINE
TRANSIT PERFORMANCE. MUNI IS ESSENTIAL FOR MOVING
LARGE CAR CROWDS AND WE NEED TO KNOW HOW TO MAKE SURE THE
AGENCY HAS ENOUGH SERVICE, STAFFING AND OPERATIONAL
FLEXIBILITY TO SERVE EVENTS LIKE THE FOURTH.
LARGE EVENTS ARE BECOMING MORE COMMON IN SAN FRANCISCO AND AS
WE CONTINUE TO HOST CELEBRATIONS, SPORTING EVENTS
AND MAJOR CIVIC GATHERINGS, OUR TRANSPORTATION PLANNING MUST
EVOLVE ALONGSIDE CHANGING TRAVEL PATTERNS AND EMERGING
TECHNOLOGIES. WE'RE ASKING AGENTS TO PROVIDE
DATA AND NOT JUST ANECDOTES INCLUDING RIDERSHIP, CONGESTION
METRICS, INCIDENT TIMELINE, AUTONOMOUS VEHICLE IMPACTS,
EMERGENCY RESPONSE INFORMATION AND LESSONS LEARNED.
THE GOAL IS STRAIGHTFORWARD. WE WANT TO ENSURE THAT FUTURE
EVENTS ARE BETTER COORDINATED, BETTER COMMUNICATED AND BETTER
MANAGED SO PEOPLE CAN CELEBRATE WITHOUT THE TRANSPORTATION
NETWORK GRINDING TO A HALT. >> WE APPRECIATE THE AGENCY'S
RESPONSES AND LOOK FORWARD TO WORKING COLLABORATIVELY ON
IMPROVEMENTS THAT STRENGTHEN THE SAN FRANCISCO'S ABILITY TO
SAFELY HOST MAJOR EVENTS. >> THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD SUPERVISOR
RANDLEMAN AREA. >> LET'S GO TO OUR 2:30 P.M.
SPECIAL ORDER IS THE SPECIAL ORDER AT 230 IS THE RECOGNITION
OF COMMENDATIONS FOR MERITORIOUS SERVICE TO THE CITY
AND COUNTY SAN FRANCISCO. >> AND WE WILL START TODAY WITH
DISTRICT TEN SUPERVISOR WALTON .
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH PRESIDENT OF COLLEAGUES TODAY IT IS MY
GREAT HONOR TO RECOGNIZE AN EXTRAORDINARY COMMUNITY LEADER
DEDICATED VOLUNTEER AND STEADFAST CHAMPION OF SAN
FRANCISCO KEITH GOLDSTEIN. HIS LIFE IS A TESTAMENT TO HARD
WORK, RESILIENCE AND SERVICE. >> KEITH JOURNEY BEGAN IN THE
COUNCIL FLATS OF LONDON'S EAST END WHERE HE WAS RAISED
ALONGSIDE HIS TWO BROTHERS. WHILE MANY EXPECTED HIS PATH TO
FOLLOW A FAMILIAR COURSE. KEITH EARNED A SCHOLARSHIP TO
UNIVERSITY ARRIVING AS A YOUNG MAN INTENT ON BECOMING A
STATISTICIAN. BUT LIFE HAD OTHER PLANS.
HE LEFT UNIVERSITY WITH A SPIRIT OF ADVENTURE DETERMINED
TO MAKE A LIFE IN SAN FRANCISCO .
A DREAM HE FULFILLED IN 1973. WHEN KEITH ARRIVED IN OUR CITY
HE HAD LITTLE MORE THAN DETERMINATION BROKE
AND SLEEPING ON THE FLOOR ON HAIGHT STREET.
HE FOUND WORK AS A HOUSE PAINTER EARNING JUST $2 AN HOUR
WITH ENTREPRENEURIAL SPIRIT AND RELENTLESS PERSEVERANCE.
HE CONVINCED A LOCAL FISH AND CHIP SHOP OWNER TO LET HIM
PAINT THE BUILDING. LAUNCHED HIS OWN BUSINESS
AND NEVER LOOKED BACK. OVER THE NEXT FOUR DECADES,
KEITH AND HIS CREWS RESTORE IT AND PAINTED MORE THAN 4000
BUILDINGS THROUGHOUT SAN FRANCISCO.
HELPING PRESERVE THE VERY CHARACTER AND HISTORY OF THE
CITY WE LOVE. >> AMONG HIS PROUDEST
ACCOMPLISHMENTS WAS LEADING THE HISTORIC RESTORATION OF THIS
VERY BUILDING WHERE WE GATHER TODAY A LASTING CONTRIBUTION TO
SAN FRANCISCO'S ARCHITECTURAL LEGACY.
>> BUT KEITH'S GREATEST IMPACT EXTENDS FAR BEYOND THE
BUILDINGS HE RESTORED. >> SINCE MAKING PATROL HERE HIS
HOME IN 1974, HE HAS DEVOTED COUNTLESS HOURS TO
STRENGTHENING THE NEIGHBORHOOD AND THE PEOPLE WHO CALL IT
HOME. >> FOR THE PAST 25 YEARS HE HAS
SERVED AS PRESIDENT OF THE PATRIOT DOGPATCH MERCHANTS
ASSOCIATION HELPING LOCAL BUSINESSES THRIVE.
>> HE HAS SERVED ON THE BOARD OF THE CHURCH BOOSTERS SINCE
2004. CHAIRED THE EASTERN
NEIGHBORHOOD CITIZEN'S ADVISORY COMMITTEE AND FOR THE PAST 16
YEARS HAS CO-CHAIRED THE BELOVED BETRAYAL HILL FESTIVAL
CREATING TRADITIONS THAT BRING NEIGHBORS TOGETHER YEAR AFTER
YEAR. >> HIS COMMITMENT TO SERVING
OTHERS REACHES ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO AND BEYOND.
AS BOARD PRESIDENT OF THE GOLDEN GATE SENIOR SERVICES FOR
THE PAST 15 YEARS HE HAS HELPED ENSURE THAT OLDER ADULTS IN OUR
COMMUNITY RECEIVE THE CARE DIGNITY AND SUPPORT THEY
DESERVE. >> SINCE 1989 HE HAS FAITHFULLY
VOLUNTEERED WITH FOOD RUNNERS SPENDING COUNTLESS SATURDAY
AFTERNOONS RESCUING THOUSANDS OF POUNDS OF SURPLUS FOOD FROM
THE FERRY PLAZA FARMER'S MARKET AND DELIVERING IT TO SHELTERS
TURNING WHAT HAVE BEEN WASTE INTO NOURISHMENT FOR THOSE
IN NEED. >> HE ALSO SERVES AS TREASURER
OF AVENUE GREEN LIGHT AND AS CO-FOUNDER AND PRESIDENT OF
NEPAL. >> SEEDS HAS SPENT NEARLY THREE
DECADES IMPROVING LIVES AND REMOTE VILLAGES ACROSS
NEPAL. THROUGH EDUCATION, HEALTH
AND COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT BEHIND EVERY REMARKABLE PUBLIC
SERVANT IS A STRONG SUPPORT SYSTEM AND KEITH HAS BEEN
FORTUNATE TO SHARE HIS LIFE'S JOURNEY WITH HIS WIFE DONNA FOR
47 WONDERFUL YEARS. TOGETHER THEY HAVE BUILT NOT
ONLY A LIFE BUT A LEGACY. AND KEITH CONSIDERS HIMSELF
ESPECIALLY LUCKY TO HAVE HIS FAMILY SETH JEREMY, ETHAN
AND MATTHEW LIVING JUST TWO DOORS AWAY.
KEITH STORY REMINDS US THAT WHERE WE BEGIN DOES NOT
DETERMINE WHERE WE END FROM THE STREETS OF EAST LONDON TO
BECOMING ONE OF SAN FRANCISCO'S MOST DEDICATED CIVIC LEADERS.
HE HAS SHOWN US WHAT IS POSSIBLE WHEN TALENT IS MATCHED
WITH DETERMINATION, GENEROSITY AND AN UNWAVERING COMMITMENT TO
COMMUNITY. ON BEHALF OF THE DISTRICT TEN
OFFICE ESPECIALLY THE RESIDENTS OF PETRO HILL AND DOGPATCH, WE
THANK YOU KEITH, FOR YOUR DECADES OF LEADERSHIP,
VOLUNTEERISM AND SERVICE. YOUR LEGACY IS REFLECTED NOT
ONLY IN THE BUILDINGS YOU HELP PRESERVE BUT IN THE STRONGER,
MORE CONNECTED AND MORE COMPASSIONATE COMMUNITY YOU
HAVE HELPED BUILD. COLLECT.
CONGRATULATIONS, KEITH, AND THANK YOU FOR EVERYTHING
YOU HAVE DONE FOR SAN FRANCISCO.
>> AND AS YOU CAN SEE, AS MANY PEOPLE WHO SHOWED UP.
YOUR LEGACY WILL ALWAYS BE REMEMBERED.
TO ALL OF US, THANK YOU SO MUCH .
AND BEFORE YOU SAY A FEW WORDS BEFORE YOU SAY A FEW WORDS, I
HAVE A COUPLE OF COLLEAGUES WHO ALSO WANT TO SPEAK AS WELL.
SUPERVISOR DORSEY, THANK YOU PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN AND I WANT
TO THANK SUPERVISOR WALTON BOTH BOTH FOR AN EXCELLENT CHOICE
AND FOR AN EXCELLENT JOB OF RECOGNIZING SOMEONE SO WORTHY
OF OUR RECOGNITION. I'VE KNOWN KEITH FOR MANY YEARS
. FIRST AS AN AFFABLE
AND ENGAGING REGULAR AT MY HEALTH CLUB BACK WHEN IT WAS
CALLED SPORTS CLUB L.A. AND THEN I THINK IT WAS A
COUPLE OF YEARS LATER WHEN I LEARNED YOU WERE ALSO A POTRERO
BOOSTER AND FRIEND OF MY FORMER BOSS DENNIS HERRERA AND CIVIC
LEADER IN YOUR OWN RIGHT. I JUST WANT TO SAY THANKS SO
MUCH FOR YOUR SERVICE TO OUR CITY, KEITH.
I WANTED TO JOIN SUPERVISOR WALTON IN EXPRESSING MY OWN
APPRECIATION AND JUST TO CONGRATULATE YOU ON THIS
WELL-DESERVED RECOGNITION. >> SUPERVISOR CHAN THANK YOU.
I WANT TO TAKE THIS PRIVILEGE AND I AS NOW THE DISTRICT ONE
SUPERVISOR BUT TO SAY THAT AS A FORMER LEGISLATOR AGES ADVISOR
SOPHIA MAXWELL KEITH YOU HAVE ALWAYS BEEN KIND AND EVEN THOSE
DAYS YOU MAY NOT REMEMBER THAT MY TIME WITH SUPERVISOR MAXWELL
BUT I REMEMBER YOU FOR YOUR ALL YOUR CONTRIBUTION TO THE
COMMUNITY ONGOING AND EVEN ALONG WITH LATE JOE AS I
RECALL LIKE OFTEN TIME VISIT SUPERVISOR SOPHIE MAXWELL'S
OFFICE SPENDING YOUR TIME TO REALLY MAKE SURE THAT WE DO THE
RIGHT THING IN DISTRICT TEN OFFICE SERVING THE COMMUNITY SO
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP AND IT'S REALLY GOOD
TO SEE YOU AND CONGRATULATIONS .
>> THE FLOOR IS YOURS. WELL, THANK YOU ALL.
THAT'S VERY, VERY TOUCHING. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR WALTON MATT AND CONNIE CHAN AND THE REST OF
THE BOARD FOR THOSE LOVELY WORDS.
SUPERVISOR WALTON MENTIONED THAT MY COMPANY THAT I FOUNDED
HERE EVEREST WATERPROOFING REPAIRED THE EXTERIOR OF THE
BUILDING. WHAT I DIDN'T KNOW IS THAT I
ACTUALLY LOST MY ON THIS JOB. I IN FACT I LOST SO MUCH MONEY
I THOUGHT I WAS GETTING NAMING RIGHTS TO THE BUILDING.
RIGHT. KEITH GOLDSTEIN CITY HALL
SOUNDS PRETTY GOOD TO ME. BUT THIS WHOLE JOURNEY STARTED
WHEN I RAISED MY HANDS TO ASK THE QUESTION AT EMERGENCY
MEETING. I HAD NO IDEA WHAT I WAS
GETTING MYSELF INTO. 25 YEARS LATER I CAN TELL YOU
IT WAS THE BEST HAND WAVE OF MY LIFE.
GETTING TO KNOW YOU ALL AND OUR COMMUNITY HAS BEEN ONE OF THE
GREAT JOYS OF MY LIFE. AND I CAME HERE AS AN IMMIGRANT
AND YOU KNOW, TWO BUCKS AN HOUR FOR A DECENT PAINTING COMPANY.
BUT I HAD AN EASY PATH BECAUSE I DO SPEAK THE LANGUAGE QUITE
WELL AND I HAVE THE RIGHT SKIN COLOR.
BUT MY COMPANY EVEREST HAD A PROGRAM OF HIRING A LOT OF
REFUGEES, PARTICULARLY FROM NEPAL AND TIBET.
THE MAJORITY OF MY EMPLOYEES WERE THAT AND I'M SO THANKFUL
TO THEM AND THEY NOT ONLY MADE MY LIFE SO MUCH BETTER BUT IT'S
THE REFUGEES AND IMMIGRANTS THAT MAKE OUR COUNTRY SO MUCH
BETTER. >> SO SOME OF YOU KNOW THAT
I'VE BEEN DEALING WITH SOME BIG TIME HEALTH ISSUES THE PAST 15
YEARS. I'VE HAD ALL SORTS OF CANCER
TREATMENTS OVER THE YEARS THAT HAVE FRANKLY KICKED MY AND THE
RUPTURED APPENDIX EARLIER THIS YEAR ALMOST TOOK ME OUT.
BUT WE GOT UCSF HERE, YOU KNOW ,AND I CAN WALK DOWN TO THE
UCSF MISSION BAY AND THANKS TO THEM I'VE STILL MANAGED TO
LEAVE THIS RIDICULOUSLY RICH, FUN, FULL PRODUCTIVE
AND MEANINGFUL LIFE. AND I HAVE TO TELL YOU I HAD A
BIG TIME SKIING YESTERDAY AND I JUST GOT THE RESULTS TODAY
AND IT SEEMS THAT THE METASTATIC CANCER IS BEING
BEATEN BACK AND I AM NOW IN A PRETTY GOOD REMISSION.
>> SO IT'S A DAY FOR A DOUBLE CELEBRATION.
SO WE'RE GOING TO PARTY AT GOAT HILL PIZZA.
JOIN ME PLEASE AT 4:00 WE'LL HAVE FOOD BEVERAGE IS THE BEST
PIZZA IN THE CITY. IN CONCLUSION I JUST FOR ME IT
BELONGS TO MY FRIENDS, MY NEIGHBORS, THE WHOLE PITCHER
HILL AND DOGPATCH COMMUNITY. MY NEPALI FAMILY AND ESPECIALLY
MY DARLING WIFE DONNA AND YOU HAVE ALL GIVEN ME A LOT MORE
THAN I'VE GIVEN YOU. >> SO THANK YOU SUPERVISORS
AND THANK YOU EVERYBODY TO YOU THAT REALLY KIND OF
ALL RIGHT. DISTRICT 11 SUPERVISOR CHEN,
THANK YOU FOR PRESENT. >> MAY I ASK DOROTHY TO COME TO
THE PODIUM? >> COLLEAGUE IT'S MY GREAT
HONOR TO CELEBRATE TO HONOR DOROTHY YOUNG, FOUNDER OF THE
CALIFORNIA DRAGON BOAT ASSOCIATION AND RETIRED
PHYSICAL THERAPIST WHO IS A BELOVED LEADER FIRST PADDLER
AND FOUNDATIONAL PILLAR TO THE SAN FRANCISCO JARGON COMMUNITY
. WHEN DOROTHY STARTED DRAGON
BOAT RACING IN 1990S IT WAS MORE THAN JUST A HOBBY OR A
SPORT. IT WAS A CALL TO ACTION TO
SUPPORT WIDER COMMUNITY NEEDS. DOROTHY AND FRANCES HAVE LI HAS
BEEN HELPED BRING THE DRAGON BOAT TRADITION TO SAN FRANCISCO
TO HELP FUNDRAISE FOR HER SISTER'S ORGANIZATION SO HELP
FOR THE ELDERLY WITH FOR PORRO THAT DRAGON BOATS A FIERY
PASSION AND A COMMUNITY DETERMINATION.
THEY FOUND THE CALIFORNIA DRAGON BOAT A ASSOCIATION
AND FORM A LONG LASTING PARTNERSHIP BETWEEN A NONPROFIT
SPORTS ORGANIZATION AND A NONPROFIT SOCIAL SERVICES
ORGANIZATIONS. THROUGH 30 YEARS OF
VOLUNTEERING AND BEHIND THE SCENES SERVICES, DOROTHY HAS
NOT ONLY WATCH BUT FOSTER THE CALIFORNIA DRAGON BALL
ASSOCIATION INTO BECOMING THE LARGEST YOUTH DRAGON BOAT
PROGRAM IN THE LEAGUE IN THE NATION PROMOTING THE GROWTH
AND DEVELOPMENT OF THE SPORT AND STRENGTHENING YOUTH
LEADERSHIP AND COMMUNITY BONDS. DOROTHY ALSO FOUND THE FIRST
WOMAN TEAM IN SAN FRANCISCO NAMED WOMAN WARRIORS BREAKING
THE BARRIERS IN A TRADITIONALLY MALE DOMINATED SPORT.
THROUGH TIRELESSLY OUTREACH, FUNDRAISING AND BEHIND THE
SCENES AWARD DOROTHY HAS IN ENSURING THAT DRAGON BOAT
RACING REMAINS ACCESSIBLE FOR ALL.
SHE CHAMPIONS THE DRAGON BOAT SPIRIT OF COMMUNITY TEAMWORK
AND UNITY. HER PASSION FOR PADDLING HAS
NEVER FADED EVEN AFTER NUMEROUS WORLD CHAMPIONSHIPS AND AWARDS
TO HER CLOSEST FRIENDS. >> SHE IS A SUPER WOMAN.
WHY DOROTHY IT'S ALMOST 80 YEARS OLD SO YOU CONTINUE TO
SHOW US THAT AGE TRULY JUST A NUMBER.
HER TIRELESS COMMITMENT, PASSIONATE LEADERSHIP
AND INFECTIOUS POSITIVE SPIRIT HAS HELPED CARRY THE DRAGON
BOAT TRADITION FOR MAKE SPACE FOR OTHERS TO BE PART OF IT
AND HELP OTHERS TO BUILD IDENTITY CONNECTIONS AND A
SENSE OF BELONGING. THANK YOU SO MUCH, DOROTHY.
>> AND OF COURSE YOU ALL ARE STUCK.
DOROTHY, BEFORE YOU. >> SUPERVISOR CHEN.
SORRY, DOROTHY. >> I JUST WANT TO SAY THAT I
DON'T KNOW IF YOU'RE GOING TO BRING THIS UP, BUT WHEN I MET
YOU TO TALK ABOUT THIS DRAGON BOAT IT WAS EARLY IN THE
MORNING. BUT WHAT INSPIRED ME YOU
INSPIRE ME AND IT'S AMAZING YOU'RE SURE THAT SHIRT WITH ME
THAT WE'RE DETERMINED TO EARNED IT THROUGH DRAGON BOAT PART
PRACTICING SUPERVISOR CHEN AND I ARE ON IT.
>> WE'RE GOING TO DO THIS AND IT'S AMAZING BECAUSE I
THINK THAT IT REALLY FITS WHO YOU ARE AND THAT'S WHO WE MUST
WORK HARD AND ASPIRE TO BE WOMAN WARRIOR AND THAT IS A
SHIRT THAT YOU HAD ON AND WE'RE JUST SO AMAZED BY WHO YOU'VE
BEEN AND WHO YOU CONTINUE TO BE TO ALL OF US.
>> SO THANK YOU FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP.
THANK YOU. >> NOW I'M REALLY EMBARRASSED.
GOOD AFTERNOON. >> DISTINGUISHED GUESTS.
A ROLL AND FRIENDS FROM 31 YEARS AGO.
>> I'M TRULY HONORED AND VERY GRATEFUL TO RECEIVE THIS
RECOGNITION. >> THANK YOU.
>> WHEN I FIRST BECAME INVOLVED IN DRAGON BOATING BACK IN THE
1990S IT WAS NEVER ABOUT PERSONAL RECOGNITION.
>> IT'S ABOUT BRINGING PEOPLE TOGETHER TO SERVE THE COMMUNITY
. >> AND MY LATE HUSBAND FRANCIS
AND I HAD THE PRIVILEGE OF WORKING WITH VERY TALENTED
PEOPLE. SOME OF THEM ARE STILL HERE
WITH ME 31 YEARS LATER. >> AND LEADERSHIP GROUPS,
COMMUNITY LEADERS AND EVERYONE WAS SO ENTHUSIASTIC.
BECAUSE DRAGON BOATING WAS NOT EVEN HEARD IN SAN FRANCISCO,
VERY FEW PEOPLE KNEW WHAT IT WAS.
IT'S A 2000 YEAR OLD TRADITION. >> AND WE FORMED THE CALIFORNIA
DRAGON BOAT ASSOCIATION FOR 23 NONPROFIT.
YOU KNOW HOW IT IS. IT'S A LONG PROCESS TO GET INTO
NONPROFIT STATUS. >> AND WHAT BEGAN AS A GREAT
EFFORT WAS SELF-HELP FOR THE ELDERLY.
MY SISTER IS HERE TO ATTESTED. SHE WAS THE ONE THAT GOT ME
EXCITED BECAUSE IT WAS A FUNDRAISING AND IT'S A
COMMUNITY THING. IT'S NOT ABOUT ME OR ATHLETIC.
>> I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW HOW TO HOLD A PADDLE AT THAT TIME.
>> AND IT BECAME MY PASSION. IT BECAME MY PASSION BECAUSE IT
TAUGHT ME TO BE A TEAM. YOU HAVE TO BE A TEAMMATE.
YOU HAVE TO COOPERATE. YOU HAVE TO COLLABORATE.
YOU HAVE TO SACRIFICE. IT'S NOT ABOUT YOURSELF.
IT'S ABOUT THE COMMUNITY AT LARGE.
>> OVER THE PAST THREE DECADES MY HUSBAND AND I HAD BEEN
IN ALL ASPECTS OF THE DRAGON BOAT NOT ONLY ADMINISTRATION
AND BUT WE HAD TO DO A LOT OF OUTREACHING.
>> WE HAD TO DO A LOT OF BOAT MAINTENANCE INCLUDING THE HOT
WORK, THE LABOR WORK, YOU KNOW THE MENTAL WORK AND ALL THAT
GOES TOGETHER WITH A VERY NEW SPORT AND THE SPORT BECAME SO
POPULAR THAT WE ENCOURAGE ALL HIGH SCHOOLS TO ENTERTAIN THE
IDEA BECAUSE STUDENTS OFTEN DON'T LISTEN TO THE TEACHERS.
BUT AFTER DRAGON BOATING THE MARVELOUS CORPORATIONS THAT
TEAMS UP VERY DIFFICULT BECAUSE THEY HAVE DIFFERENT OPINIONS
IN THE DRAGON BOAT YOU ALL HAVE TO LISTEN TO THE COACH ONE
CALL, ONE DISCIPLINE. >> AND WHEN THEY RETURN TO THE
CORPORATION SUPERVISORS, SENIOR EXECUTIVES ALL WORK IN HARMONY.
>> AND THAT'S BECAUSE OF WHAT THEY LEARNED IN DRAGON BOATING.
>> IT'S A SPORT BUT IT'S ALSO A REAL LIFE EXPERIENCE.
>> SO I'M VERY THANKFUL TO FORM THE FIRST WOMEN'S TEAM BECAUSE
IT'S STILL SOMETHING I CHERISH FOR 30 SOME YEARS.
IT WAS CALLED THE WOMAN WARRIORS AND IT WAS THE FIRST
EVER BECAUSE IT'S A VERY MALE DOMINANT SPORT.
SO NOW WE HAVE MEN AND WOMEN ALL ENTHUSIASTIC ABOUT THE
SPORT, ABOUT THE COMMUNITY, ABOUT THE SERVICE.
>> WHEN THEY CALL ME SUPER WOMAN.
I AGAIN WE INNOVATE AT 80 YEARS OLD.
>> I CAN DO WHAT A 20 YEAR OLD CAN DO.
>> SO IT'S SOMETHING TO REMEMBER.
>> AGE IS JUST A NUMBER. >> MM HMM.
OKAY. I CAN DO A HUNDRED PUSHUPS
AGAIN. >> THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THIS
INCREDIBLE HONOR. I REALLY WANT TO SHARE IT WITH
MY HUSBAND, MY FAMILY, MY FRIENDS, MY TEAMMATES, PEOPLE
WHO VOLUNTEER FOR 31 YEARS AND ASK STILL TO VOLUNTEER.
>> IT'S SUCH A PRIVILEGE TO KEEP MOVING FORWARD AND AGAIN,
THANK YOU FOR THE RECOGNITION. >> VERY
. >> UP NEXT FROM DISTRICT THREE
SUPERVISOR SOLDER. >> THANK YOU, PRESIDENT.
GENTLEMEN, COLLEAGUES, TODAY I HAVE THE HONOR OF WELCOMING
GLORIA CHOI TO THE CHAMBERS. >> SO, MISS CHOI AND IF YOU
COULD COME UP AND ALL ALL THE STUDENTS AS WELL ALL OF YOUR
ADMIRERS, EVERYONE APPLAUDING COME ON UP AND JOIN AS WELL,
PLEASE. PRINCIPAL CHOI, THANK YOU FOR
BEING HERE. PRINCIPAL CHOI RETIRED LAST
MONTH AFTER 37 YEARS WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO UNIFIED SCHOOL
DISTRICT. >> SHE BEGAN HER CAREER AS A
PARAPROFESSIONAL AT SPRING VALLEY ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN 1989 AFTER GRADUATING FROM UC BERKELEY AND SHE THEN SPENT
20 YEARS AS A KINDERGARTEN TEACHER BEFORE SERVING MULTIPLE
GENERATIONS OF CHINATOWN FAMILIES AS PRINCIPAL OF GORDON
J. LAO.
MANY OF YOU KNOW THAT GORDON HELOU IS THE LARGEST ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN SAN FRANCISCO. SO YOU HAVE HAD YOUR HANDS FULL
FOR ALL OF THESE YEARS. YOUR ENTIRE EDUCATION CAREER
HAS BEEN DEDICATED TO SERVING SAN FRANCISCO OUR CHILDREN, OUR
FAMILIES. AND YOUR CONNECTION TO
CHINATOWN I KNOW IS DEEPLY PERSONAL.
>> MR. CHOI IMMIGRATED TO SAN FRANCISCO FROM PERU WHEN SHE
WAS FIVE YEARS OLD. SHE GREW UP IN CHINATOWN
IN NORTH BEACH AND ATTENDED ST PETER'S AND PAUL BEFORE
GRADUATING FROM WASHINGTON HIGH SCHOOL.
HER FAMILY OWNED A BAKERY IN CHINATOWN WHERE SHE HELPED
ALONGSIDE HER PARENTS WHO WORKED INCREDIBLY HARD WHILE
RAISING EIGHT CHILDREN DESPITE NOT SPEAKING ENGLISH.
>> THEIR SACRIFICES SHAPED HER APPRECIATION FOR EDUCATION,
PERSEVERANCE AND COMMUNITY. MR. ALWAYS OWN FAMILY IMMIGRANT
EXPERIENCE HELPED GIVE HER A DEEP UNDERSTANDING OF MANY OF
THE STUDENTS AND FAMILIES THAT SHE HAS SERVED OVER THESE YEARS
. AND THROUGHOUT HER CAREER SHE
HAS BEEN GUIDED BY THE BELIEF THAT EVERY CHILD DESERVES TO
FEEL SAFE, CHALLENGED AND LOVED .
DURING HER TIME IN GORDON J LAO SHE WORKED TO BUILD STRONG
PARTNERSHIPS AMONG FAMILIES SCHOOL STAFF, COMMUNITY
ORGANIZATIONS AND CITY AGENCIES BECAUSE SHE BELIEVES EDUCATING
CHILDREN IS A COMMUNITY EFFORT AND STRONG SCHOOLS HELP BUILD
STRONG NEIGHBORHOODS. MR. WRIGHT MY MOTHER IS A
RETIRED HIGH SCHOOL TEACHER SO I HAVE A SMALL PEEK INTO THE
IMPORTANCE OF YOUR WORK, THE SCOPE OF YOUR IMPACT EVEN
THOUGH YOU ARE RETIRING AS YOU KNOW YOUR IMPACT LIVES ON.
AND FOR THE STUDENTS HERE TODAY THEY PROBABLY DON'T QUITE GRASP
THIS YET BUT ONE DAY THEY WILL AS I HAVE AS WE ALL HAVE WHICH
IS JUST THE THE MAGNITUDE OF HOW STUDENTS OF HOW TEACHERS,
MENTORS, PRINCIPALS SHAPE US. AND IT IT'S KIND OF THE BEAUTY
OF IT IS IT TAKES A LOT OF TIME AND EXPERIENCE AND REFLECTION
FOR THAT TO BE UNDERSTOOD. BUT YOU'VE DONE THAT.
YOU'VE MADE THAT IMPACT FOR DECADES NOW FOR 37 YEARS.
SO WE ARE SO GRATEFUL TO YOU. WE'RE SO GRATEFUL FOR YOUR
LEGACY AT GORDON TO ALLOW AT SFO A CITY CHINATOWN IN ALL OF
SAN FRANCISCO. CONGRATULATIONS ON YOUR
WELL-EARNED RETIREMENT. THE FLOOR IS YOURS TO SAY A FEW
REMARKS AND THANK YOU. >> GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISOR
SAUDER MEMBERS OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS FAMILY, FRIENDS,
COLLEAGUES AND STUDENTS THANK YOU FOR THIS INCREDIBLE HONOR.
THIS RECOGNITION IS ESPECIALLY MEANINGFUL BECAUSE IT GIVES ME
THE OPPORTUNITY TO CELEBRATE THE PEOPLE WHO MAKE THESE 37
YEARS SO REWARDING. I WOULD LIKE TO BEGIN BY
ACKNOWLEDGING MY FORMER AND CURRENT STUDENTS DANNY
BESIDE ME HERE TODAY. SOME ARE CURRENT QUADRANGLE
STUDENTS WHILE OTHERS ARE FORMER STUDENTS WHO ARE NOW
PREPARING TO BE IN COLLEGE THIS FALL OR ALREADY HAVE BEGUN
THEIR CAREERS. >> I INVITED THEM TO STAND BY
ME BECAUSE THEY REPRESENT THE THOUSANDS OF STUDENTS
AND FAMILIES WHO HAVE BEEN THE HEART OF MY 37 YEARS
IN EDUCATION. >> ONE OF THE GREATEST
PRIVILEGES OF MY LIFE HAS BEEN WATCHING CHILDREN GROW INTO
GROW INTO CARING ADULTS WHO CONTRIBUTE TO THEIR COMMUNITIES
AND INTO MAKING THIS WORLD A BETTER PLACE.
>> I WAS BORN IN PERU AND CAME TO SAN FRANCISCO WHEN I WAS
FIVE YEARS OLD. >> I GREW UP IN CHINATOWN NORTH
BEACH NEIGHBORHOOD AND ATTENDANCE SINCE PETER
AND PAUL AND LATER GRADUATED FROM WASHINGTON HIGH SCHOOL.
MY FAMILY OWNED A BAKERY IN CHINATOWN AND I GREW UP
HELPING THERE WHILE MY PARENTS WORKED TIRELESSLY AND TO
SUPPORT OUR FAMILY OF EIGHT. >> I'M NUMBER SEVEN IN CASE
YOU'RE INTERESTED AND IT WAS NOT EASY AND THOSE EXPERIENCES
HELPED ME UNDERSTAND THE CHALLENGES OF BUILDING A NEW
LIFE IN A NEW COUNTRY. >> I BEGAN MY CAREER AS A
KINDERGARTEN TEACHER AND SPENT 20 YEARS TEACHING OUR YOUNGEST
LEARNERS. >> LATER I HAD THE PRIVILEGE OF
SERVING AS PRINCIPAL OF GORDON J.
LAO ELEMENTARY SCHOOL. WHENEVER I SPOKE TO NEWCOMERS,
STUDENTS AND THEIR FAMILIES I SAW MY OWN FAMILY.
I UNDERSTOOD THE HOPES AND STRUGGLES OF THE FAMILIES I
SERVE ACROSS EVERY ROLE. MY MISSION REMAINED THE SAME TO
ENSURE THAT EVERY CHILD FELT SAFE, VALUED, CHALLENGED
AND LOVED AND THAT EVERY FAMILY FELT WELCOME AND RESPECTED.
>> TO THE FAMILIES OF GORDON J. LAO, THANK YOU FOR TRUSTING ME
WITH YOUR CHILDREN. TO MY COLLEAGUES AND STAFF.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR PARTNERSHIP AND DEDICATION TO MY FAMILY
AND FRIENDS. THANK YOU FOR YOUR LOVE, YOUR
ENCOURAGEMENT AND UNWAVERING SUPPORT THROUGHOUT MY CAREER.
I COULD NOT HAVE DONE THIS WITHOUT YOU AND TO MY STUDENTS.
THANK YOU FOR GIVING MY WORK MEANING JOY AND PURPOSE.
>> YOU TAUGHT ME RESILIENCE, COMPASSION AND HOPE.
>> AFTER 37 YEARS I HAVE LEARNED THAT MY GREATEST
ACCOMPLISHMENT HAS BEEN THE RELATIONSHIPS THAT I HAVE BUILT
ALONG THE WAY. AND THE PRIVILEGE OF WATCHING
GENERATIONS OF STUDENTS GROWING INTO CARING COMPASSIONATE
ADULTS. >> I'M ON MY LAST PAGE.
>> SO WHILE I AM DEEPLY HONORED TO RECEIVE THIS COMMENDATION
TODAY, I WANT EVERYONE HERE TO KNOW THAT THIS RECOGNITION
TRULY BELONGS TO THE STUDENTS, THE FAMILIES, STAFF
AND COMMUNITY WHO MADE IT POSSIBLE FOR ME TO SPEND MY
LIFE DOING WORK THAT I REALLY LOVE.
BECAUSE OF YOU I AM VERY BLESSED.
>> THANK YOU FOR GIVING ME THE OPPORTUNITY TO SERVE SAN
FRANCISCO CHILDREN'S AND FAMILIES FOR THE PAST 37
YEARS. >> I WILL ALWAYS CARRY THE
GOLDEN CHILD OUT COMMUNITY IN MY HEART.
>> I AM DEEPLY GRATEFUL FOR THIS HONOR AND MOST GRATEFUL
ACTUALLY. FOR THIS WILL BE MY LAST SPEECH
THAT I WILL EVER HAVE TO DO. >> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WOW. OKAY.
WE JUST GOT SOME PICTURES
. >> CAPTAIN WILHELM, COME ON UP
. COLLEAGUES, TODAY I AM HONORED
TO PRESENT A SPECIAL COMMENDATION TO CAPTAIN ANGELA
WILHELM OF THE SAN FRANCISCO POLICE DEPARTMENT WHO UNTIL A
FEW MONTHS AGO WAS THE CAPTAIN AT PARK STATION.
>> THROUGHOUT HER CAREER, CAPTAIN WILHELM HAS EMBODIED
THE DEPARTMENT'S CORE PRINCIPLES OF SERVICE
COMPASSION, HONESTY AND DIVISION.
SHE CAME TO SAN FRANCISCO WHEN SHE WAS 18 YEARS OLD AND HAS
BEEN WITH THE DEPARTMENT FOR 27 YEARS GRADUATING WITH THE 192ND
RECRUIT CLASS AND RISING THROUGH THE RANKS FROM
DEDICATED SERGEANT AND ANALYTICAL LIEUTENANTS TO
HER APPOINTMENT AS A COMMANDING OFFICER.
AS HEAD OF PARK STATION, CAPTAIN WILHELM RECOGNIZED THAT
NEIGHBORHOOD SAFETY RELIES ON VISIBILITY AND EXPANDED FOOT
PATROLS ALONG BUSY STREETS AND PUBLIC SPACES.
SHE QUICKLY ESTABLISHED HERSELF AS AN ACCESSIBLE LEADER FOR
LOCAL BUSINESSES AND COMMUNITY GROUPS.
SHE WORKED WITH THE COAL VALLEY MERCHANTS ASSOCIATION TO ENSURE
THE SAFE OPERATION OF NEIGHBORHOOD EVENTS LIKE COAL
VALLEY NIGHTS. SHE FOCUSED ON PARTNERSHIPS
WITH LOCAL ORGANIZATIONS ADDRESSING QUALITY OF LIFE
CONCERNS INCLUDING TRAFFIC SAFETY, HOMELESSNESS
AND WORKING WITH CITY PARTNERS ON PUBLIC SPACE MAINTENANCE.
PRIOR TO COMMANDING PARK STATION, THE CAPTAIN SPENT TEN
YEARS IN THE TENDERLOIN AS AN OFFICER FOR ALMOST HER ENTIRE
PATROL TIME. SHE TRAINED RECRUITS AND TAUGHT
AT THE ACADEMY UNTIL SHE WAS PROMOTED TO SERGEANT IN 2013.
SHE ALSO SERVED IN INTERNAL OVERSIGHT ROLES AT THE
DEPARTMENT AS LIEUTENANT IN CHARGE OF THE INTERNAL
AFFAIRS DIVISION FOR FOUR AND A HALF YEARS AT CENTRAL STATION.
BEYOND HER OPERATIONAL DUTIES, CAPTAIN WILHELM IS A CHAMPION
FOR MENTAL HEALTH AWARENESS CRISIS SUPPORT AND COMMUNITY
LIFE. SHE'S PARTICIPATED IN PUBLIC
CAMPAIGNS FOR THE NATIONAL ALLIANCE ON MENTAL ILLNESS TO
BRING ATTENTION TO THE COMPLEXITIES OF MENTAL HEALTH
CRISES. >> AND SHE STEPPED IN TO JUDGE
THE COAL VALLEY NIGHTS PIE BAKING CONTEST AS WELL AS
MCKINLEY ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS DOG FEST AND LOTS OF OTHER
OBLIGATIONS OUTSIDE OF DISTRICT EIGHT AS WELL.
I'M SURE DAY IN AND DAY OUT CAPTAIN WILL HOME ADDRESS
COMPLEX QUALITY OF LIFE ISSUES MANAGED SAFETY DEPLOYMENTS,
DEPLOYMENTS AND MAINTAINED OPEN COMMUNICATION WITH RESIDENTS.
IT IS BITTERSWEET TO SEE CAPTAIN WHEEL HOME TO PARK
STATION AFTER WHAT TO MY MIND WAS NOT NEARLY ENOUGH TIME BUT
WE WERE FORTUNATE TO BE ABLE TO WORK WITH HER DURING HER
POSTING AT PARK. I AM EXCITED TO SEE HER
PROMOTED TO HER NEW POSITION AS A STAFF SERVICES CAPTAIN IN THE
ADMINISTRATION BUREAU AND KNOW THAT SHE WILL CONTINUE TO SERVE
SAN FRANCISCO WELL IN HER NEW ROLE IN CHARGE OF PERSONNEL
AND RECRUITMENT INITIATIVES AND SUPPORTING THE REBUILDING
THE RANKS PROGRAM TO FULLY STAFF S.F. PD WHICH IS
IMPORTANT AND MAY BE WORTH LOSING YOU FROM PARK STATION.
CAPTAIN, WE THANK YOU. WE CONGRATULATE YOU.
I HAVE SOME COLLEAGUES WHO ALSO WANT TO SAY NICE THINGS ABOUT
YOU. BEFORE WE ALLOW YOU TO SPEAK
WITH THAT SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD THANK YOU, PRESIDENT, FOR
GIVING THIS COMMENDATION. >> EXCITED FOR YOU CAPTAIN
WILHELM. I THINK BACK TO ON THE FIRST
TIME WE MET THERE HAD JUST BEEN AN INCIDENT IN A SMALL BUSINESS
WHERE THEY HAD COME UNDER A PUBLIC SAFETY CONCERN.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO DO SO I JUST WALKED INTO PARK STATION.
>> IT WAS EARLY ON IN MY TENURE AND YOU WERE THERE AND I THINK
THAT WAS ALSO YOUR FIRST DAY AS CAPTAIN OF PARK STATION AS WELL
. >> BUT YOU IMMEDIATELY SPRUNG
INTO ACTION. AFTER EMPATHY YOU MET WITH THE
SMALL BUSINESS. WE ADDRESS THEIR CHALLENGES.
AND I THINK DURING THE TIME WE WORKED TOGETHER I THINK THAT'S
CONTINUED TO BE I'VE KNOWN YOU AS SOMEONE WHO TAKES THE
INITIATIVE, WORKS WITH EMPATHY AND YOU'RE JUST KIND OF ALWAYS
THERE. EVERY EVENT WE'VE BEEN AT
IN THE HATE. I'VE ALWAYS SEEN YOU THERE OR
YOUR OFFICERS HELPING TO MAKE IT SAFE FOR EVERYONE.
WE'VE DISCUSSED NITROUS OXIDE ISSUES THANKFUL FOR MY
COLLEAGUE WHO'S NOT HERE WHO'S WORKING ON THAT AS WELL.
AND JUST VERY EXCITED THAT YOU'VE HAD A PERMANENT IMPACT
ON THE NEIGHBORHOOD AND THE DISTRICT AS WELL BRINGING THE
FIRST A TRAFFIC SAFETY OFFICER BACK TO HATE STREET.
THAT HAS BEEN SOMETHING THE COMMUNITY HAS BEEN ASKING FOR
FOR SO LONG. AND NOW WE HAVE DEDICATED
PERSON WORKING ON TRAFFIC ENFORCEMENT BUT ALSO EDUCATION.
AND THAT IS A LASTING INVESTMENT THE NEIGHBORHOOD IS
GOING TO THANK YOU FOR FOR SO MUCH TIME.
BUT WE ARE VERY GLAD TO HAVE YOU NOW WORKING ON RECRUITMENT
WHICH IS THE THORNIEST PROBLEM IN THIS OF PD.
AND WE'RE HERE TO SUPPORT AND WE'RE EXCITED FOR YOU
CONTINUE TO STEER THE SHIP THERE AS WELL TO THANK YOU FOR
ALL YOU'VE DONE AND THANK YOU FOR ALL YOU WILL DO AS WELL.
>> SUPERVISOR MELGAR THANK YOU PRESIDENT FOR THIS INSPIRED
COMMENDATION AND I ALSO WANTED TO ADD MY VOICE TO MY
COLLEAGUES AS A DISTRICT THAT ALSO IS SERVED BY PARK STATION.
>> SO I WON'T REPEAT SOME OF THE THINGS THAT MY COLLEAGUES
HAVE SAID ABOUT YOU YOUR INVOLVEMENT IN THE COMMUNITY,
YOUR ABILITY TO TAP INTO THE NEEDS OF THE COMMUNITY AND AND
JUST SAY AS A MOTHER AND YOU KNOW, I SO ADMIRE YOUR
TRAJECTORY, YOUR WARMTH, YOUR STRATEGY AND DESPITE BEING I
WAS REALLY BUMMED OUT WHEN I HEARD THAT WE WERE LOSING YOU
FOR REAL AND I TOLD YOU NO AT CHIEF LEW I WASN'T HAPPY ABOUT
IT. BUT THEN WHEN I HEARD WHERE YOU
WERE GOING I ACTUALLY AM SUPER EXCITED ABOUT IT.
SO I. I AM REALLY LOOKING FORWARD
AND I THINK YOU'RE THE RIGHT PERSON IN ADDRESSING THE ISSUES
OF RECRUITMENT OF FEMALE STAFF AS A PD AND ALL OF THE ISSUES
AROUND AND YOU KNOW THINKING THROUGH AS SUPPORT AND MENTAL
HEALTH AND YOU KNOW ADVANCEMENT OPPORTUNITIES AND I CAN'T THINK
OF A BETTER ROLE MODEL THAN YOU FOR ALL OF THESE THINGS.
SO I AM I THINK ACTUALLY IT'S PRETTY INSPIRED THAT YOU'RE
WHERE YOU ARE AND I'M GRATEFUL THAT WE'LL GET TO WORK TOGETHER
ON THOSE ISSUES IN THE FUTURE. I THANK YOU FOR YOUR SERVICE AT
PARK STATION AND THANK YOU PRESIDENT FOR THIS COMMENDATION
AND THANK YOU CAPTAIN WILHELM THE FLOOR IS YOURS.
>> THANK YOU. IT'S IT'S I'M SO HUMBLED
AND REALLY HONORED AND TOUCHED TO HAVE BEEN CAN YOU SPEAK
DIRECTLY INTO THAT MICROPHONE? THANK YOU.
SORRY, I'M JUST SO HONORED AND HUMBLED AND TOUCHED TO BE
RECOGNIZED. THANK YOU, PRESIDENT MANDOLIN.
THANK YOU TO THE BOARD AS I WAS JUST SORT OF REFLECTING ON MY
TIME AT PARK STATION AND MEETING ALL OF YOU I
THOUGHT ABOUT THAT MY VERY FIRST DAY IN THE LOBBY AT PARK
STATION WHEN WE MET AND WHAT REALLY STRUCK ME, SUPERVISOR
MAHMOOD REALLY WAS YOUR CARE, COMPASSION, JUST GENUINE
COMMITMENT TO THE COMMUNITY. I MET I MET SUPERVISOR CHAN AT
NATIONAL NIGHT OUT. THANK YOU FOR YOUR SUPPORT
SUPPORTING PUBLIC SAFETY, SUPPORTING THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT. I MET SUPERVISOR MELGAR
AND TWIN PEAKS AND THANK YOU FOR JUST REAFFIRMING THAT WOMEN
ARE IMPORTANT IN PUBLIC SAFETY AND YOU KNOW I INTEND TO SORT
OF CONTINUE THAT ON MAKING SURE WE'RE RECRUITING WOMEN IN MY
NEW ROLE. PRESIDENT MANDELL MAN, I CAN'T
THANK YOU ENOUGH FOR YOUR YOUR MENTORSHIP, YOUR GUIDANCE, YOUR
LEADERSHIP EVENTS AT THE DUBBO'S NEIGHBORHOOD TRIANGLE
CAVALLI AND ALSO SUPERVISOR CHERYL WORKING ON A NUISANCE
ISSUE IN DISTRICT TWO. I WOULDN'T BE HERE WITHOUT YOU
KNOW, THE SUPPORT OF PARK STATION.
I COULDN'T HAVE DONE THIS ALONE .
I YOU KNOW, I REALLY WISH TO CALL ATTENTION TO THE MEMBERS
OF PARK STATION FOR HELPING ME IN THIS ROLE.
I'VE HAD SOME REALLY KEY PEOPLE NOT ONLY IN THE COMMUNITY BUT
ON MY STAFF THAT HAVE SUPPORTED ME ALSO AT HOME MY HUSBAND
CAPTAIN CRISWELL WILHELM, OFFICER JEFF SUNG, A FEW OTHERS
THAT COULDN'T BE HERE TODAY OFFICER RON KWOK, RUBEN RHODES
TREMAINE WASHINGTON. SO I REALLY SHARE THIS
RECOGNITION WITH ALL OF THEM. >> THANK YOU GUYS SO MUCH.
I REALLY APPRECIATE THIS. THIS FOR HERE JUST FOR YOU ONE
MORE RIGHT EVERYBODY ALL RIGHT MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO BACK TO
ROLL CALL. >> YES, MR. PRESIDENT.
YOU WOULD BE LAST IN LINE ON THE ROLL CALL FOR
INTRODUCTIONS. >> OKAY.
ALL RIGHT, FOLKS, I GOT AN ORDINANCE HEARING AND TWO
IN MEMORIAM. FIRST TODAY I AM INTRODUCING
LEGISLATION TO PROVIDE PROVIDE TAX RELIEF TO SMALL INDEPENDENT
HARDWARE STORES THROUGHOUT SAN FRANCISCO.
THESE STORES HAVE SEEN SIGNIFICANT INCREASES TO THEIR
GROSS RECEIPTS TAX BURDENS SINCE PASSAGE OF PROP M IN 2024
AND THIS MEASURE WILL PROVIDE SOME MUCH NEEDED RELIEF.
SAN FRANCISCO I DON'T THINK I NEED TO TELL YOU LOVES OUR
NEIGHBORHOOD HARDWARE STORES IN DISTRICT EIGHT COAL HARDWARE
AND CLIFFS VARIETY ARE FAMILY OWNED BUSINESSES THAT HAVE BEEN
SERVING THEIR NEIGHBORHOODS FOR A CENTURY.
FOR GENERATIONS, RESIDENTS HAVE TURNED TO THESE NEIGHBORHOOD
HARDWARE STORES NOT JUST FOR TOOLS AND SUPPLIES BUT FOR
ADVICE AND EXPERTISE FROM STAFF ON EVERYTHING FROM HOME REPAIRS
TO CREATIVE PROJECTS DURING THE COVID PANDEMIC THESE STORES
WERE LITERALLY LIFE SAVERS. >> BUT THE REALITY IS THAT
BELOVED OR NOT, NEIGHBORHOOD HARDWARE STORES ARE STRUGGLING
. IN ADDITION TO COMPETITION FROM
CHAINS AND ONLINE RETAILERS, NEIGHBORHOOD HARDWARE STORES
ARE ALREADY OPERATING ON RAZOR THIN MARGINS HAVE HAD TO DEAL
WITH RETAIL THEFT TARIFFS AND EVER INCREASING OPERATING
EXPENSES. STORE OWNERS HAVE BEEN SOUNDING
THE ALARM ABOUT HOW DIFFICULT IT IS TO KEEP THEIR DOORS OPEN
IN RECENT YEARS AND IN DECEMBER OF 2020 FOR PAPA ANNOUNCING
HARDWARE IN WEST PORTAL CLOSED AFTER 88 YEARS IN BUSINESS
IN 2024 SAN FRANCISCO VOTERS PASSED PROPOSITION M A MAJOR
REFORM OF OUR BUSINESS TAX STRUCTURE DESIGNED TO INCREASE
THE CITY'S ECONOMIC RESILIENCE ADAPT TO POST-COVID HYBRID WORK
PATTERNS, CREATE MORE TRANSPARENCIES FOR TAXPAYERS
AND PROVIDE RELIEF TO SMALL BUSINESSES.
AT LEAST THAT WAS THE INTENTION .
THE MEASURE RESULTED FROM EXTENSIVE ANALYSIS
AND STAKEHOLDER CONSULTATION AND WAS ULTIMATELY PUT ON THE
BALLOT BY SIGNATURE GATHERING EFFORT OUTSIDE CITY HALL.
HOWEVER, EVEN BEFORE PROP EM PASSED I HAD BEGUN TO HEAR
CONCERN FROM SMALL HARDWARE STORES THAT CONTRARY TO THE
INTENT OF PROP M THEY WERE IN A CATEGORY OF SMALL BUSINESS THAT
MIGHT ACTUALLY SEE THEIR THEIR TAX BURDEN INCREASE IF THE
MEASURE PASSED. AND IN FACT NOW THAT THE DUST
OF THAT CAMPAIGN HAS SETTLED AND BUSINESSES HAVE BEGUN TO
RECEIVE THEIR POST PROP M TAX BILLS, THESE BUSINESSES ARE
SEEING SIGNIFICANT INCREASES IN WHAT THEY OWE.
>> THIS ORDINANCE WOULD REMEDY THAT UNINTENDED CONSEQUENCE BY
CREATING A TAX CREDIT FOR SMALL HARDWARE RETAILERS WHO MEET TWO
REQUIREMENTS FIRST, MORE THAN HALF OF THEIR COMBINED GROSS
RECEIPTS COMING WOULD BE WOULD HAVE TO COME FROM QUALIFYING
HARDWARE PRODUCTS. AND SECOND, THEY WOULD HAVE TO
HAVE LESS THAN $50 MILLION IN COMBINED GROSS RECEIPTS FROM
ALL SOURCES DURING A TAX YEAR. THESE THRESHOLDS ARE DESIGNED
SPECIFICALLY TO TARGET RELIEF TOWARD SMALL INDEPENDENT
COMMUNITIES SERVING HARDWARE STORES.
I WANT TO THANK TERRY AUSTIN BENNETT FROM CLIFF'S VARIETY
STORE. RICK KARP FROM CALLS FROM COLE
HARDWARE, KAREN ASHFORD FROM FREDRICKSON HARDWARE AND JAMIE
GANTNER FROM CENTER HARDWARE AND SUPPLY COMPANY FOR SHARING
THEIR EXPERIENCES FOR THEIR PARTNERSHIP ON THE LEGISLATION.
I ALSO WANT TO THANK SCOTT REBER AND CHARLES OLSON FROM
THE CITY ATTORNEY'S OFFICE AS WELL AS BRAD RUSSI, TED EGAN
FROM THE COMPTROLLER'S OFFICE ERIC MANKIW AND AMANDA FREED
FROM THE TREASURY TAX COLLECTORS OFFICE AND GRACE
WONG ON MY STAFF FOR HER WORK. >> SECONDLY, COLLEAGUES, TODAY
I'M CALLING FOR A HEARING TO DISCUSS SAN FRANCISCO'S
PREPARATION AND READINESS FOR EXTREME WEATHER EVENTS.
ON MARCH 20TH, SAN FRANCISCO HIT 90°F.
THAT WAS THE FIRST TIME IN 152 YEARS OF RECORDS THAT THE CITY
HAD REACHED 90 DEGREES IN MARCH.
THAT EVENT SHOULD FEEL ALARMING BUT IT IS CONFIRMED WITH THE
SCIENCE HAS BEEN TELLING US THE CLIMATE THAT HAS LONG PROTECTED
SAN FRANCISCO FROM HEAT IS CHANGING.
THIS IS NOT JUST A SAN FRANCISCO PROBLEM.
LAST MONTH EUROPE FOUND ITSELF IN THE GRIP OF WHAT SCIENTISTS
CALLED ITS MOST SEVERE HEATWAVE ON RECORD.
FRANCE POSTED ITS HOTTEST DAY IN HISTORY.
THE UK KNOWN FOR ITS GRAY SKIES AND MILD SUMMERS WAS UNDER A
RED WARNING FOR EXTREME HEAT FOR THREE CONSECUTIVE DAYS
SOMETHING THAT HAD NEVER HAPPENED IN THE HISTORY OF THE
COUNTRY'S WARNING SYSTEM. THE PATTERN IS THE SAME ACROSS
THE WORLD. CITIES AND BUILDINGS NOT
DESIGNED FOR HEAT, RESIDENTS NOT ACCLIMATED TO IT
AND INSTITUTIONS CAUGHT UNPREPARED.
>> WE OFTEN THINK OF SAN FRANCISCO AS A NATURALLY COOL
OASIS AIDED BY THE OCEAN AND OUR FOG.
>> BUT OUR VULNERABILITY IS REAL AND SPECIFIC.
OUR BODIES ARE NOT ACCLIMATIZED TO HEAT BECAUSE OUR HEAT
ARRIVES IN BRIEF INTENSE SPIKES.
OUR BUILDINGS HAVE THE LOWEST AIR CONDITIONING RATE OF ANY
MAJOR AMERICAN CITY. 34% OF HOUSEHOLDS AGAINST
NATIONAL AVERAGE OF 92% AND RISING NIGHTTIME
TEMPERATURES ARE ELIMINATING THE OVERNIGHT RECOVERY WINDOW
THAT LETS BODIES AND BUILDINGS COOL DOWN BEFORE THE NEXT DAY'S
HEAT RETURNS. THE BURDEN OF THAT
VULNERABILITY IS NOT EVENLY DISTRIBUTED.
WHEN HEAT ARRIVES IN SAN FRANCISCO, IT HITS HARDEST
IN NEIGHBORHOODS LIKE SOMA, BAYVIEW, HUNTERS POINT
AND CHINATOWN. URBAN HEAT ISLANDS THAT RUN
SIGNIFICANTLY HOTTER THAN SURROUNDING AREAS AND WHOSE
RESIDENTS ARE THE LEAST LIKELY TO HAVE ACCESS TO COOLING.
THE ELDERLY, THE UNHOUSED AND LOWER INCOME RESIDENTS
AND ASTROS FACE COMPOUNDING RISKS LESS ACCESS TO AIR
CONDITIONING, GREATER EXPOSURE TO INDOOR HEAT TO OUTDOOR HEAT
AND IN MANY CASES UNDERLYING HEALTH CONDITIONS THAT MAKE
EXTREME TEMPERATURES PARTICULARLY LIFE THREATENING.
NOW WE HAVE SOME SENSE OF WHAT HAPPENS WHEN A MAJOR HEAT EVENT
STRIKES ON SEPTEMBER 1ST, 2017 .
THE CITY HIT 106 DEGREES. THREE PEOPLE DIED IN SAN
FRANCISCO, THREE MORE IN SAN MATEO COUNTY.
ALL ELDERLY ALONE AND AT HOME BETWEEN 3 AND 4 IN THE
AFTERNOON THAT DAY 19 CALLS WERE WAITING FOR AMBULANCES
IN THE CITY HAD NONE TO SEND. THAT BACKLOG REACHED 36 CALLS
BY 5 P.M.. COOLING CENTERS WERE NOT
AUTHORIZED UNTIL AFTER 10 P.M. AFTER THE PEAK OF THE EMERGENCY
HAD PASSED. AN NBC BAY AREA BAY AREA
INVESTIGATION LATER FOUND THE CITY HAD A DECADE OLD RESPONSE
PLAN THAT IT DID NOT USE. THAT WAS NEARLY NINE YEARS AGO
AND IN MAY OF 2023 THE OFFICE OF RESILIENCE AND CAPITAL
PLANNING AND TEAM RELEASED THE HEAT AND AIR QUALITY RESILIENCE
PLAN LAYING OUT 31 STRATEGIES TO MAKE THE CITY MORE RESILIENT
TO EXTREME WEATHER. >> BUT SEVERAL YEARS LATER,
MANY OF THESE STRATEGIES HAVE YET TO BE IMPLEMENTED AND THE
QUESTION ARE HEARING WILL SEEK TO ANSWER IS WHEN AN EXTREME
WEATHER EVENT STRIKES AGAIN BECAUSE IT IS A QUESTION OF
WHEN AND NOT IF IS SAN FRANCISCO IN A BETTER POSITION
TO RESPOND? I WANT TO THANK OUR ACP TEAM
AND THE DEPARTMENT OF THE ENVIRONMENT FOR THEIR
ASSISTANCE, ASSISTANCE AND THINKING THROUGH THIS
HEARING. I LOOK FORWARD TO HEARING FROM
THEM AT THE HEARING AS WE WORK TOGETHER TO ENSURE SAN
FRANCISCANS ARE PROTECTED FROM THE EXTREME WEATHER EVENTS THAT
WE KNOW ARE COMING. I ALSO WANT TO THANK RENE
AUBERJONOIS AND MY OFFICE FOR HIS WORK ON THIS.
>> I'M ASKING COLLEAGUES THAT WE ADJOURN TODAY'S MEETING
IN MEMORY OF JEFF LITTLEFIELD WHO SERVED AS CHIEF OPERATING
OFFICER OF SAN FRANCISCO INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT UNTIL HE
DIED UNEXPECTED ODDLY AT THE AGE OF JUNE AT THE AGE OF 62
IN JUNE. HIS CAREER IN AVIATION SPANNED
SEVERAL DECADES AFTER HOLDING LEADERSHIP ROLES AT TWC AMERICA
WEST AND UNITED AIRLINES AND SERVING AS GENERAL MANAGER
AT OAKLAND INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT.
HE JOINED SFO IN 2008 AS AS AIRPORT DUTY MANAGER.
HE QUICKLY ROSE THROUGH THE RANKS BECOMING DEPUTY AIRPORT
DIRECTOR FOR OPERATIONS AND SECURITY IN 2011 AND HE WAS
APPOINTED CHIEF OPERATING OFFICER IN 2016.
>> BEFORE THE PANDEMIC SFO WAS THE SEVENTH LARGEST AIRPORT
IN THE UNITED STATES SERVING NEARLY 58 MILLION PASSENGERS
ANNUALLY AND EMPLOYING APPROXIMATELY 46,000 PEOPLE.
AS CEO, JEFF OVERSAW ALL ASPECTS OF AIRPORT OPERATIONS
INCLUDING AIRPORT OPERATIONS AND SECURITY FACILITIES THE SFO
MUSEUM AND THE AIRPORT AND BUREAUS FOR BOTH THE SAN
FRANCISCO POLICE DEPARTMENT AND THE FIRE DEPARTMENT.
HIS LEADERSHIP AND EXPERTISE WERE INSTRUMENTAL IN GUIDING
SFO THROUGH THE COVID 19 PANDEMIC.
ONE OF THE MOST CHALLENGING PERIODS IN THE HISTORY OF
AVIATION DURING THIS TIME HE WAS FACED WITH DIFFICULT
OPERATIONAL DECISIONS INCLUDING HOW TO MANAGE THE TEMPORARY
CLOSURE OF BOARDING AREAS WHILE ALSO COORDINATING TESTING
AND VACCINATION EFFORTS AND HELPING TO CHART THE
AIRPORT'S PATH TO RECOVERY. >> JEFF WAS DEEPLY COMMITTED TO
EQUITY AND INCLUSION, SERVING AS A MENTOR AND ROLE MODEL TO
EMPLOYEES OF COLOR, CHAMPIONING THE ADOPTION OF EQUITY AS A
CORE VALUE AT SFO LEADING DEVELOPMENT OF THE AIRPORT'S
RACIAL EQUITY ACTION PLAN AND HELPING ESTABLISH
AND SUPPORT EMPLOYEE RESOURCE GROUPS INCLUDING BIPOC AT SFO.
OUTSIDE OF WORK HE ENJOYED COOKING, TRAVELING, STAYING
ACTIVE AND SPENDING TIME WITH THE FAMILY AND FRIENDS HE LOVED
THOSE THAT WORKED WITH JEFF DESCRIBED HIM AS THE HEART
AND SOUL OF SFO AND A FORCE FOR GOOD.
REST IN PEACE JEFF LITTLEFIELD. MAY YOUR MEMORY BE A BLESSING.
AND SECONDLY, COLLEAGUES, I'M ASKING THAT WE ADJOURN TODAY'S
MEETING IN MEMORY OF IRA SANDLER.
SAN FRANCISCO'S KING OF CLUBS AND THE FOUNDER AND LONGTIME
OWNER OF 1015 FOLSOM. HE DIED OF A HEART ATTACK AT
THE END OF MAY AT THE AGE OF 70 THREE.
>> BORN AND RAISED IN BROOKLYN, SANDLER GREW UP THE SON OF TWO
EDUCATORS AND ATTENDED STUYVESANT HIGH SCHOOL.
AFTER GRADUATING FROM SUNY BUFFALO WITH A MASTER'S DEGREE
IN MEDIA, HE MOVED TO CALIFORNIA AND BEGAN WORKING AS
A PROFESSIONAL PHOTOGRAPHER. HE EVENTUALLY WENT BACK TO
SCHOOL TO STUDY FINE ART PHOTOGRAPHY AT THE SAN
FRANCISCO ART INSTITUTE WHERE HE BEGAN THROWING EVENTS THAT
BROUGHT TOGETHER THE ART, FASHION AND LIVE MUSIC SCENES.
IN 1986 HE WAS TAPPED TO TAKE OVER A CLUB IN SOMA, THEN KNOWN
AS MAJOR PONCE. >> HE TRANSFORMED IT INTO DANCE
CLUB AND THREE YEARS LATER IN 1989 RENAMED IT TEN FOUR
1015 FOLSOM. WHEN HE OPENED 1015 FOLSOM
NIGHTLIFE WAS DOMINATED BY LIVE ROCK AND PUNK PERFORMANCES.
1015 FOLSOM WAS ONE OF THE FIRST NIGHTCLUBS OUTSIDE OF NEW
YORK AND CHICAGO TO FEATURE ELECTRONIC MUSIC.
IT WOULD BECOME THE HEART OF SAN FRANCISCO'S 1990S RAVE
SCENE ATTRACTING DEEJAYS, ELECTRONIC MUSIC FANS
AND MEMBERS OF THE CITY'S LGBTQ PLUS COMMUNITY AND HELPING TO
DEFINE A NEW GENERATION OF NIGHTLIFE.
>> THE CLUB OPENED DURING A PARTICULARLY CHALLENGING TIME
FOR SAN FRANCISCO. THE LATE 80S AND EARLY 90S WERE
OF COURSE THE WORST YEARS OF THE AIDS EPIDEMIC AND JUST DAYS
AFTER 1015 FOLSOM OPENED ITS DOORS.
THE LOMA PRIETA EARTHQUAKE STRUCK.
DURING THOSE DIFFICULT YEARS MANY SAN FRANCISCANS REMEMBER
10 OR 15 FOLSOM AS A SANCTUARY OFFERING A PLACE WHERE PEOPLE
COULD COME TOGETHER, FIND JOY AND CONNECTION.
ALTHOUGH IRA WAS NOT A MEMBER OF THE LGBTQ PLUS COMMUNITY
HIMSELF, HE WAS AN OUTSPOKEN ALLY AT A TIME WHEN GAY RIGHTS
WAS NOT YET MAINSTREAM. HE HOSTED LGBTQ EVENTS AT 1015
FOLSOM AND PARTNERED WITH PROMOTERS.
HE ALSO REGULARLY HOSTED A FUNDRAISER TO CELEBRATE.
HE ALSO REGULARLY HOSTED FUNDRAISERS SUPPORTING THOSE
WHO HAD BEEN AFFECTED BY THE AIDS CRISIS.
>> IRA WAS KNOWN FOR RECOGNIZING TALENT AND OVER THE
YEARS 1015 FOLSOM WOULD PLAY HOST TO MANY BUDDING
AND ESTABLISHED MUSICIANS AND CELEBRITIES INCLUDING CARL
COX FAT BOYS FATBOY SLIM, DAVE CHAPPELLE KAYTRANADA
AND ANDERSON PACK. IRA EMBRACED THE UNCONVENTIONAL
AND THE UNDERDOG BOOKING UNKNOWN ARTISTS AND HELPING TO
MAINTAIN THE CLUB'S RELEVANCE ACROSS DECADES OF SHIFTING
MUSICAL AND CULTURAL TRENDS. HIS PROGRAMING EXTENDED BEYOND
ELECTRONIC MUSIC INCLUDING LONG RUNNING SATURDAY NIGHT LATIN
PARTIES AND THE ANNUAL REAL BAD FUNDRAISER EVENT WHICH HAS
RAISED MILLIONS FOR CHARITY SINCE 1999.
TODAY 1015 FOLSOM AND THE AURA OF NIGHTLIFE THAT HELPED USHER
IN REMAIN CENTRAL TO SAN FRANCISCO'S CULTURAL IDENTITY.
IRIS CREATIVITY AND HIS VISION OF A SPACE WHERE EVERYONE NO
MATTER THEIR BACKGROUND COULD BELONG CONNECT AND EXPERIENCE
JOY ARE HIS LASTING LEGACY. HE IS SURVIVED BY HIS OLDER
SISTER MAYA SHOWN. HIS OLDER BROTHER JOE DE COSTA
HIS NIECE AND TWO NEPHEWS AND ALL THE STAFF PERFORMERS
AND PERFORMERS WHO CONTRIBUTED TO THE SUCCESS OF 1015 FOLSOM
OVER THE LAST 40 YEARS. REST IN PEACE AND POWER IRA
SANDLER. MAY YOUR MEMORY BE A BLESSING
AND THE REST I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
SAYING NO NAMES ON THE ROSTER. >> THAT CONCLUDES THE
INTRODUCTION OF NEW BUSINESS THEN I BELIEVE AT THIS POINT WE
WILL GO TO GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT.
AT THIS TIME THE BOARD WELCOMES YOUR GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT.
IN PERSON SPEAKERS WILL BE PRIORITIZED SO PLEASE LINE UP
ON YOUR RIGHT HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER.
ONCE THE IN-PERSON SPEAKERS LINE IS EXHAUSTED WE WILL CALL
ON THE REMOTE SPEAKERS IF YOU ANTICIPATE PROVIDING REMOTE
PUBLIC COMMENT. THE TELEPHONE NUMBER IN THE
MEETING ID INSTRUCTION IS PUBLISHED ON THE AGENDA
AND STREAMING ON YOUR SCREEN. >> I WAS TOLD IT IS A BEST
PRACTICE TO CALL IN EARLY AS A REMINDER AS IF COVID TV IS NOT
IN SYNC WITH THIS MEETING. IT IS DELAYED BY A FEW MOMENTS
SO YOU MUST PAY ATTENTION TO THE PHONE PROMPT AND WE ASK
THAT YOU TURN DOWN YOUR TELEVISION.
DURING GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT YOU MAY SPEAK TO APPROVAL OF
THE JUNE 2ND 2026 BOARD MEETING MINUTES AS PRESENTED.
>> ITEMS 18 THROUGH 20 THE ITEMS UNDER THE ADOPTION
WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE CALENDAR.
OTHER GENERAL MATTERS THAT ARE NOT ON TODAY'S AGENDA BUT MUST
BE WITHIN THE BOARD SUBJECT MATTER JURISDICTION.
ALL OTHER AGENDA CONTENT HAS BEEN REPORTED OUT TO THE BOARD
BY AN APPROPRIATE COMMITTEE WHERE THE PUBLIC COMMENT
REQUIREMENT OCCURRED. THE TIMER ON THE WOOD PODIUM IS
SET FOR TWO MINUTES. YOU WILL HEAR A SOFT BELL WHICH
SHOULD SIGNAL YOU TO WRAP UP YOUR STATEMENT IN THE REMAINING
30S BEFORE YOU HEAR THE LOUDER BELL CHIME.
ALL RIGHT. WELCOME TO OUR FIRST SPEAKER.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS HONEST CHARLIE BODKIN,
PRESIDENT OF THE DISTRICT FIVE DEMOCRATIC CLUB.
ON JULY 4TH WAYMO'S CAUSED MAJOR TRAFFIC HAVOC AROUND
FISHERMAN'S WHARF AND NORTH BEACH AFTER THE FIREWORKS SHOW.
>> IT TOOK ME THREE HOURS TO GET MY TWO YOUNG NEPHEWS BACK
TO CIVIC CENTER WHERE THEY LIVE.
>> ONE OF THEM WAS WAY PAST THEIR BEDTIME.
WE WEREN'T JUST STUCK IN HEAVY TRAFFIC.
OUR BUS AND SEVERAL BUSSES BEHIND US WERE PHYSICALLY
BLOCKED BY MULTIPLE WAY MODES THAT WERE STALLED BECAUSE THEY
COULDN'T CONNECT TO THE INTERNET.
>> IT IS A COMPLETE MISNOMER TO CALL THESE AUTONOMOUS VEHICLES
WHEN THEY DEPEND ON THE INTERNET TO FUNCTION.
>> THEY'RE NOT AUTONOMOUS THE SAME WAY THAT HUMAN BEINGS ARE
BECAUSE OUR DEPENDENCY IS KNOWN.
>> THE MAYOR'S OFFICE, THE DEPARTMENT OF EMERGENCY
MANAGEMENT, THE S.F. MTA SHOULD HAVE RESTRICTED WAYMO'S
OPERATIONS IN THAT AREA DURING THE EVENT.
>> WE ALLOW THESE VEHICLES TO OPERATE IN AREAS WHERE WE
ALREADY KNOW THAT THEY'LL BE AFFECTED BY PLANNED PERMITTED
EVENTS. >> THAT'S UNACCEPTABLE.
SOME PEOPLE COULD HAVE STAYED HOME OR LEFT ON FOOT OR BY BIKE
BUT WARNINGS ABOUT NOT USING TRANSIT WERE SENT OUT AT 8:45
P.M.. THAT WAS 45 MINUTES BEFORE THE
FIREWORKS SHOW STARTED. >> THAT PEOPLE NOWHERE NEAR
ENOUGH TIME TO AVOID AN ENTIRELY FORESEEABLE PROBLEM
WHILE EVERYONE ELSE LOOKED LIKE THEY WERE HAVING A GREAT TIME.
I WAS STUCK ON A BUS WITH SENIORS, DISABLED PEOPLE
AND YOUNG CHILDREN FAMILIES WITH NO WAY OUT.
EVEN IF WE HAD WANTED TO TAKE A CAR WE'D HAVE HIT THE SAME
GRIDLOCK AS EVERYONE ELSE. WE SHOULDN'T ALLOW WAYMO'S INTO
AREAS WHERE WE ALREADY KNOW IN ADVANCE THAT THEY'RE LIKELY
TO FAIL. >> WAYMO MUST GIVE OFFICIALS
THAT ARE ON THE GROUND LIKE POLICE AND ASAP MTA OPERATORS
THE ABILITY TO LOCALLY CONTROL THESE VEHICLE STEERING.
I APPRECIATE THAT THERE WAS A HEARING ON THIS EARLIER THIS
YEAR BUT WHAT'S ACTUALLY BEEN DONE SINCE WE KNEW JULY FOURTH
WAS COMING? WHY HASN'T ANYTHING BEEN DONE
IN ADVANCE TO PREVENT THIS? WE'RE ASKING OUR LEADERS TO
LEAD WHAT'S GOING ON? I'D LIKE TO THANK MY SUPERVISOR
DISTRICT FIVE SUPERVISOR BELAL MAHMOOD FOR JOINING WITH ME TO
ASK THESE QUESTIONS. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS HONEST.
WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER. >> GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS ERIC SEDGLEY. I'M A 52 YEAR OLD RESIDENT OF
SAN FRANCISCO ESPECIALLY THE WESTERN EDITION.
I WANT TO THANK OUR SUPERVISORS FOR STEPPING UP DISTRICT FIVE
AND I ALSO WANT TO THANK FOR THE PROTECTION AS I CAME IN OF
THE CALIFORNIA SAN FRANCISCO HISTORY AND NEVER FORGET THE
HISTORIC REMOVAL IN THE WESTERN TRADITION THAT WE'RE
STILL FIGHTING TO GET AND UNDERSTANDING OF WHERE DO
WE STAND RIGHT? >> AND OVER THE YEARS THE 25
YEARS NOW I'VE BEEN INVOLVED AS A YOUNG MAN INTO THE AGE I AM
NOW AND WE'VE HAD CONSULTANTS AFTER CONSULTANTS AFTER
CONSULTANTS. WE'VE HAD MEETINGS WHERE WE PUT
POSTED NOTICES DOTS ON THE WALL.
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH THAT FOR 25 YEARS AND YET WE'RE STILL GOING
THROUGH IT WITH THIS NEW FILM OR WHATEVER WE WANT TO CALL IT
WITH THE DIFFERENT DEPARTMENTS .
I WANT TO KNOW PERSONALLY AND I'M SURE THE DISTRICT WANTS
TO KNOW WHERE DOES THE BUDGET LINE IS IN THE WEST AND WE GOT
ALL THESE DIFFERENT DEPARTMENTS.
ECONOMIC AND WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT HAS BEEN IN OUR
COMMUNITY SINCE REDEVELOPMENT CLOSED AND HAS AN OPEN UP OF
BLACK BUSINESSES TO BLACK BUSINESSES IN THE 25 YEARS THAT
I'VE BEEN AROUND. WE HAVE A NEW LATINO BUSINESS.
WE HAVE A NEW CORNER STORE BUSINESS.
WE GOT SUPERDUPER RIGHT. WE HAVE NEW BUSINESS AND THAT'S
YOU KNOW, SAYING THAT WE SHOULDN'T BUT I'M JUST TRYING
TO FIGURE OUT WHERE DOES THE AFRICAN-AMERICAN COMMUNITY LIE
IN 2026 AFTER ALL THIS HISTORIC MESS THAT WE'VE BEEN THROUGH
THAT WE KEEP GOING THROUGH? I JUST I WANT TO HEAR IN ON THE
DEPARTMENTS ESPECIALLY ECONOMIC AND WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT WHERE
DOES THE BUDGET LIES AS LINE ITEMS AS THEY ASK DIFFERENT
NONPROFITS EACH CITY ACCOUNTING SERVICE TO ACCOUNT FOR YOUR
MONEY AND MAKE THEM ACCOUNT FOR THEIR MONEY.
>> THANK YOU ERIC SALAZAR FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER .
>> BORROW SUPERVISORS. MAYOR OFFERS A SAN FRANCISCO
DANIEL LURIE THE TITLE OF THIS SPEECH IS THREE TYPES OF
CONVERSATION A DOCTOR WORK 30 YEARS TO TREAT CANCER PATIENTS
FULFILLING HIS OBLIGATION TO GET HIS PATIENT SCANNED
AND RECOMMENDS REGIMEN AND PROCEDURES A HUGE AND AN
INFLECTION POINT. >> HE NOTICED THAT THE MOST
MORTALITY OF HIS PATIENT WAS HIGHER THAN HIS COLLEAGUE SO HE
GOES CALLING HIS COLLEAGUE TO PLEA FOR AN ANSWER.
>> WHY AFTER MUTUAL PLEASE YOU GOT AN ANSWER.
HE WAS ASKING THE WRONG QUESTION.
IT TURNS OUT DON'T TREAT THREE TYPES OF CONVERSATION.
THE FIRST TYPE MOST PEOPLE DEAL WITH WAS WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
HOW IS IT? WHAT IS IT?
SECOND IS THAT EMOTIONAL CONVERSATION.
AND THIRD IS A DEEP AND A CONVERSATION.
>> MAJORITY OF PEOPLE AS MENTIONED AS THE FIRST ONES.
BUT INSTEAD WE SHOULD ENGAGE ASKING THE SECOND ONE HOW DO
YOU FEEL? FOR EXAMPLE, I CALL THE CHASE
CENTER AND GLENN MEMORIAL MY HOME.
HOW WOULD YOU FEEL IF YOU COME TO MY HOME AND HAVE A LITTLE
TOUR OF MY HOME? NOW THAT GOES TO MY LAST
CONVERSATION TO DEEP AND CONVERSATION.
I AM IT TOOK ME TWO YEARS TO ASK THIS THAI GIRL FOR PHONE
NUMBER. I NEVER KISSED HER.
I NEVER TOUCHED HER. TWO YEARS FOR ME.
ASK ONE HOUR LATER MY BEST FRIEND CALLED ME UP TO ASK FOR
A SPONSORSHIP FOR HONG KONG. SHE CAME UP WITH MISS CHINESE
INTERNATIONAL TITLE AND I'M HERE TO TACKLE THE $340 MILLION
BUDGET DEFICIT. IT IS DIFFICULT BUT IT'S
DOABLE. THE MINUTE YOU HAVE CONTENT OH
MY GOD IT'S NOT GOING TO WORK. >> TRUST ME I WOULD GET A JOB
DONE BECAUSE I WOULD DO IT. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. CAN WE HEAR FROM OUR NEXT
SPEAKER? WELCOME.
THANK YOU FOR LETTING ME SPEAK. IMPROMPTU I RUSHED OVER FROM
THE LIBRARY. >> I KNOW THIS PARTY ISN'T THE
FORUM FOR MY REQUEST. I JUST AM IN DESPERATE HEALTH.
I WENT TO THE SAN FRANCISCO HUMAN SERVICES TO GET ENROLLED
WITH THEIR CASH AID PROGRAM. >> BUT I DIDN'T MEET THE
MINIMUM QUALIFICATIONS BECAUSE I DON'T HAVE ENOUGH SWIPES ON
MY ABT CARD TO SHOW THAT I'M A RESIDENT.
AND I'VE BEEN HERE FOR TWO MONTHS.
THE THING IS IS THAT I'M REALLY TRYING TO YOU GUYS USE THE
SERVICES HERE AS A HOMELESS PERSON NAVIGATING THE PROGRAMS
THAT YOU HAVE. BUT I KEEP HITTING THESE
ROADBLOCKS. I'M LIKE THERE'S GOT TO BE A
WAY TO MAKE IT EASIER. SO I HAVE MVP CARD.
IT'S IT'S FREE FOOD. THANK YOU GUYS.
I APPRECIATE THAT. BUT I ALSO NEED A JOB.
AND SO I'M GOING TO THESE FOLKS GOING HOW DO I GET IN CONTACT
WITH YOUR EMPLOYMENT SERVICES SO THAT I CAN START GETTING
NETWORKED IN THE SYSTEM? BUT I HAVE TO WAIT TILL AFTER
GENERAL ASSISTANCE GETS KICKED OFF IN A MINUTE AND WORK WITH
THEM. >> THERE'S A THREE WEEK LAG.
OKAY. SO THE OTHER THING IS IS THAT
THOSE OF US THAT ARE HOMELESS WE'RE DEALING WITH SO MANY
MAGNITUDE ISSUES THAT THE SAND BENEATH OUR FEET JUST KEEPS
SHIFTING. YOU NEED A CELL PHONE BUT YOU
CAN'T GET A CELL PHONE AND A COMPUTER AT THE SAME TIME.
THERE'S NO BUSINESS HERE THAT ALLOWS US TO MAKE CALLS AND GET
INTERNET ACCESS TO HAMMER THINGS OUT.
AND YOU ONLY GET LIKE MAYBE 15 MINUTES OR 20 MINUTES WITH A
PHONE BUT YOU GET TWO HOURS WITH A COMPUTER.
IT'S A MESS AND THEY'RE ALL DIFFERENT LOCATIONS SO WE'RE
GETTING SCRAMBLED. BUT THE OTHER THING IS IS THAT
AS I'M LIVING IN GOLDEN GATE PARK I RUN OFF 3040 THIRD
STREET OFF LINCOLN. I LOOK DOWN AT MY MY MY TENT
AREA AND I SEE ALL THESE MOTORCYCLE TRACKS.
AND THERE'S A TRACKER WITH FISH AND GAME.
I LOOK BACK AND THERE'S LIKE THIS ATV FOR MOTORCYCLES
AND SOME POINT IN THE MORNING JUST DRIVE UP TO MY TENT
AND STOP AND THEN COME OUT AND THEY TAKE IT APART.
HELLO WE'RE DOING BUT I'M LIKE I DON'T KNOW WHO THESE ATV
FOLKS ARE BUT ANYWAY I THINK YOU GUYS.
>> THANKS. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER .
>> HI. HI SUPERVISORS.
I WILL BE BRIEF. MY NAME IS DAVID WURTZEL.
I AM THE PRESIDENT AND GENERAL MANAGER OF KGO-TV ABC7.
AND I JUST WANTED TO SAY THAT KGO IS PROUD OF ITS RECORD OF
SERVING SERVING THE PUBLIC INTEREST IN THE BAY AREA FOR A
LONG TIME. >> AND WE'RE HONORED THAT THE
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS IS BRINGING UP A RESOLUTION ON OUR
BEHALF. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, DAVE WERFEL FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME. MR. RIGHT.
>> SAME TO YOU AS A VIEWER PLEASE.
I WANT TO START OFF WITH THIS BUDGET FOR CITY COLLEGE.
>> CITY COLLEGE IS GETTING APPROXIMATELY.
MR. RIGHT CAN YOU SPEAK TO THE MICROPHONE PLEASE?
CITY CITY COLLEGE IS GETTING APPROXIMATELY $5,600,000.
I THOUGHT WE ADDRESSED THAT PROBLEM YEARS AGO WHEN JANE
KIMMEL WAS HERE. I TOLD YOU THAT HAVING STUDENTS
ATTEND $1 MILLION FACILITY FOR FREE IS GOING TO CREATE A
MULTIMILLION BILLION DOLLAR NEGATIVE CASH FLOW.
AND AS A RESULT FIVE YEARS LATER AFTER THAT HEARING MY
PREDICTIONS CAME TRUE. AND THEN YOU END UP LAYING OFF
WELL OVER SEVERAL STAFF OF TEACHERS AND I COMPLAINED
AND GOT UPSET ABOUT HOW YOU ALWAYS MAKE TEACHERS PAY FOR A
PROBLEM THAT THEY DID NOT CREATE.
NOW I'VE COME TO FIND OUT THAT YOU STILL FINANCE IN THE
COLLEGE FOR FREE. PEOPLE SHOULD BE PAYING THEIR
TUITION TO GO TO COLLEGE. THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO ALSO HAS JURISDICTION WITHIN THE UNIVERSITY OF SAN
FRANCISCO COLLEGE. THE UNIVERSITY WHICH ALSO HAS A
LAW SCHOOL. IF THEY LET THEIR STUDENTS GO
TO SCHOOL FOR FREE THEY WOULD GO BANKRUPT.
YOU'RE CREATING A MULTIMILLION DOLLAR CARES NEGATIVE CASH FLOW
AGAIN. AND I ALSO PREDICTED THAT YOU
CAN'T HAVE PEOPLE FROM 192 DIFFERENT COUNTRIES GET ON
MEDI-CAL SNAP PROGRAM AND SERVICES WHEN YOU'RE NOT
CITIZENS. AND AS A RESULT YOU'VE GOT A
600 AND $50 BILLION NEGATIVE CASH FLOW.
>> AND AS A RESULT YOU ADD DEBT.
OKAY. AND THAT'S ANOTHER UNNECESSARY
EXPENSE THAT'S TAKING PLACE. NOW CALIFORNIA OWES THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT A MINIMUM OF $1,000,000,310 MILLION.
$32,542 BECAUSE YOU'RE PUTTING PEOPLE ON THE MEDICARE SYSTEM
THAT ARE NOT ELIGIBLE JUST LIKE I COMPLAINED ABOUT.
>> SO THANK YOU, MR. WRIGHT, FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER. >> OH, OKAY.
READY? >> HI, I'M JESSICA PERSICO.
YOU GUYS ARE YOU KNOW ME. IT'S AFTER THE 4TH OF JULY.
SO I'M WEARING MY RED, WHITE AND BLUE AS YOU CAN SEE.
>> CAN'T SEE THE BOTTOMS. >> SO THE ROOM THE REASON WHY
THE ROOM IS A LITTLE BIT LIGHTER AROUND HERE IS BECAUSE
PEOPLE ARE GOING TO GO HELP PIZZA FROM 430 UNTIL 6 P.M. TO
TODAY TO HONOR KEITH GOLDSTEIN .
RETIRING PETRO DOGPATCH MERCHANTS ASSOCIATE ASSOCIATION
PRESIDENT. >> AND SO I HOPE WE CAN WRAP
THIS MEETING UP EARLY SO WE CAN ALL ATTEND.
SO THERE'S NUMBERS CONCERNS THERE'S GONNA BE ABOUT SEVEN
ONE FIRST AND 88 HOUSING SAFETY CONCERN A DISTRICT A RESIDENT
IN DISTRICT SIX FELL AND 1190 MISSION STREET HE SUFFERED A
HEAD INJURY HE ALLEGES THE BUILDING WASN'T SAFE BECAUSE IT
WASN'T BUILT FOR ADA STANDARDS AND HE FACES DISPLACEMENT ON
MEDICAL LEAVE WAS IS CAN HAPPEN ANYWHERE AT ANY TIME OLDER
APARTMENTS MUST BE ACCESSIBLE BECAUSE WE KNOW THAT PUBLIC
SAFETY IS A BIG ISSUE. IT'S NOT JUST A CODE
COMPLIANCE. >> MAY 2ND CAN WE CONFIRM OR
CAN WE JUST GET A PATROL HILL NEIGHBORHOOD HOUSING GRANT
BECAUSE THEY ARE DOING AN ARTS COMMISSION MEETING AND THERE'S
GOING TO IN PARTICULAR IS GOING TO BE THE COMMUNITY ART GALA ON
SEPTEMBER 26TH AND I HOPE WE CAN GET FUNDING FOR IT.
THIRD, I'M GOING TO SUGGEST THAT THE 24 HOUR FITNESS AT
1645 BRYANT IS NOT OPERATING AS ITS NAME SUGGESTS.
>> IT'S NOT 24 HOURS. THE FACILITY HAS BROKEN
EQUIPMENT AND HAS FAILED TO ACKNOWLEDGE COMMUNITY MOMENTS
LIKE VETERANS DAY IN 911. >> I'M ASKING WHETHER THIS
COMMERCIAL SPACE COULD BE CONVERTED INTO A YMCA SO
FUNDING BACKFLOW INTO OUR DISTRICT AND SUPPORTS REAL
YOUTH PROGRAMS. >> THANK YOU JESSICA.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. ARE THERE ANY OTHER MEMBERS OF
THE PUBLIC WHO ARE HERE IN PERSON WHO WOULD LIKE TO
ADDRESS THE BOARD DURING GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT?
ALL RIGHT. WE'LL GO TO OUR REMOTE CALLER I
UNDERSTAND WE HAVE ONE CALLER ON THE LINE.
LET'S HEAR FROM OUR CALLER. WELCOME BACK.
DOROTHY, IS A CHILD LEFT TO YOU AND YOU JUST GO TO THE NEXT
SPEAKER PLEASE. >> ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE JUST BEGINNING. ALL RIGHT, MR. PRESIDENT, THAT
CONCLUDES THE GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT.
>> ALL RIGHT. PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED.
>> AND WITH THAT, MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO THE FOR ADOPTION OF
THAT COMMITTEE REFERENCED AGENDA ITEMS 18 THROUGH 20
ITEMS 18 THROUGH 20 WERE INTRODUCED FOR ADOPTION WITHOUT
COMMITTEE REFERENCE. A UNANIMOUS VOTE IS REQUIRED
FOR ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON FIRST READING TODAY ANY MEMBER
MAY REQUIRE A RESOLUTION ON FIRST READING TO GO TO
COMMITTEE. >> SUPERVISOR JAN SUMMER MAY
18TH. >> SUPERVISOR DORSEY I WOULD
LIKE TO BE ADDED AS A CO-SPONSOR TO ITEM 18.
THANK YOU SUPERVISOR DORSEY. MADAM CLERK, COULD YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS 19 AND 20 ON ITEMS 19 AND 20
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR. EYES SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EYES
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON.
EYES SUPERVISOR WONG WONG EYES SUPERVISOR CHAN EYE CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER EYES SUPERVISOR A MAHMOOD MAHMOOD
EYE AND SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN RIGHT MANDOLIN EYE.
THERE ARE 11 EYES WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE
ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
18. ITEM 18 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO
URGE THE FEDERAL COMMUNICATIONS COMMISSION TO FAIRLY EVALUATE
AND RENEW THE BROADCAST LICENSE FOR KGO TV CHANNEL.
>> THANK YOU. PRESIDENT RANDALL
AND COLLEAGUES, I AM URGING NOT ONLY FOR YOUR SUPPORT TODAY
AND I UNDERSTAND OF COURSE WE WOULD BE HAVING IT THIS AS A
FOR ADOPTION WITHOUT REFERENCE TO COMMITTEE.
IT IS A CLEAR SHOWING THAT WE WILL BE APPROVING THIS.
BUT I DO ACTUALLY ALSO WANT TO URGE FOR YOUR CO-SPONSORSHIP SO
THANK YOU SO MUCH TO SUPERVISOR DORSEY.
>> THIS IS A CRITICAL POINT AND TIME FOR INDEPENDENT
JOURNALISM. NOT ONLY THAT I BELIEVE IN SAN
FRANCISCO BAY AREA BUT SURELY WILL IMPACT NATIONWIDE IF WE DO
NOT EXPRESS A STRONG AND AFFIRMATIVE SUPPORT FROM
THIS BODY. I THINK THAT IT WILL CREATE
RIPPLE EFFECT THAT WILL IMPACT INDEPENDENT JOURNALISM
ELSEWHERE. I WILL URGE NOT ONLY FOR YOUR
SUPPORT FOR YOUR VOTES BUT FOR YOUR CO-SPONSORSHIP WHICH I
REALLY, REALLY TRYING TO PUSH FOR THAT.
>> AND I ALSO NOT ONLY THAT I WANT TO URGE FOR YOUR SUPPORT
AND YOUR CO-SPONSORSHIP. I WOULD REALLY URGE FOR YOUR
SUPPORT TO YOUR CONSTITUENTS THAT THERE IS A PUBLIC COMMENT
PERIOD THAT WE COULD ACTUALLY INCUR.
SAN FRANCISCO RESIDENT WHO HAS BEEN BENEFITED FROM INDEPENDENT
JOURNALISM AND FROM A STATION LIKE KGO AND OTHERS THAT REALLY
SHOULD CONTAIN YOU TO ENSURE THERE'S A FAIR EVALUATION TO
THIS PROCESS. INDEPENDENT JOURNALISM IS MORE
CRITICAL THAN EVER. >> WE ALL KNOW WHAT HAPPENS
AND HOW IT IMPACTS OUR ELECTION, OUR DEMOCRACY.
I THINK WE ALL HAVE SOMEWHAT BEEN A VICTIMS WHEN THERE'S
MISINFORMATION PASSION OUT THERE NOT JUST FOR OURSELVES
BUT FOR OUR LEGISLATION, NOT THE POLICY WORK THAT WE DO
AND EVEN INCLUDING OUR COMMUNITY.
SO I JUST REALLY WANT TO URGE FOR YOUR SUPPORT AND WANT TO
ACKNOWLEDGE THAT. MR. DAVID WURTZEL THAT ACTUALLY
CAME ALL THE WAY TO JUST TO WAIT TO HAVE TWO MINUTES OF
PUBLIC COMMENTS TO SHOW YOU THAT IN PAWNS OF THIS NOT JUST
THIS LEGISLATION BUT TRULY AT THIS TIME FOR YOUR SUPPORT
THROUGH A PUBLIC COMMENT PERIOD.
THANK YOU. >> SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU
PRESIDENT MALCOLM AND I WANT TO EXPRESS MY APPRECIATION TO
SUPERVISOR CHEN FOR HER LEADERSHIP IN BRINGING THIS
FORWARD. I WILL CONFESS THAT I WOULD
PROBABLY BE IN DEFENSE OF ANY NEWS ORGANIZATION THAT IS
FACING AN OVERREACH BY THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT.
BUT I HAVE PARTICULAR AFFECTION FOR KGO-TV JUST BECAUSE OF THE
COMMITMENT THAT IT HAS SHOWN THROUGH THE YEARS.
I'VE SPENT MUCH OF MY CAREER WORKING WITH NEWS ORGANIZATIONS
. THERE'S AN ETHOS THAT INFORMS
THIS ORGANIZATION ABOUT BUILDING A BETTER BAY AREA
AND I REALLY APPRECIATE SOME OF THE LONG FORM DOCUMENTARY WORK
THAT JOURNALISTS LIKE TARA CAMPBELL HAVE DONE THAT I WILL
SAY NOT EVERY TV STATION IS COMMITTED TO BUT IT IS
SOMETHING THAT IT MEANS A LOT TO PEOPLE WHO HAVE BEEN COVERED
AROUND THE DRUG POLICY REALM THAT TARA HAS BEEN COVERING.
I KNOW THAT THERE'S RESOURCES INVOLVED IN THAT AND I REALLY
VALUE THE WORK THAT ABC SEVEN AND KGO TV DO.
SO I'M HAPPY TO BE A CO-SPONSOR OF THIS AND AGAIN THANK YOU
SUPERVISOR CHEN SUPERVISOR MELGAR, OUR CO-SPONSOR.
>> THANKS FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP AND FOR THE MUCH.
>> SUPERVISOR WALTON. THANK YOU PRESIDENT MILLIMAN
ONE I WOULD LIKE TO BE ADDED AS A CO-SPONSOR BUT TWO I JUST
WANT TO KIND OF ECHO SUPERVISOR DORSEY'S COMMENTS BUT I WANT TO
SAY THAT I HAVE SEEN KGO REALLY BE BOLD AND WHO THEY PUT
IN FRONT OF THE CAMERA, PARTICULARLY THE LAST FEW YEARS
AT A TIME WHERE WE HAVE SEEN THE SAME ANCHORS ACROSS TV
STATIONS AND MOST OF OUR CHANNELS AND TAKING RISK
AND BRINGING SUCH DIVERSITY PARTICULARLY IN THE MORNING
AND DOING IT OVER THE PAST SEVERAL YEARS AND IT JUST LOVE
TO SEE IT FROM NOT ONLY RACE ETHNICITY BUT ALSO FROM AGE
AND JUST ALLOWING OPPORTUNITIES FOR SO MANY YOUNG JOURNALISTS
TO THRIVE. SO I JUST WANT TO APPRECIATE
THEM FOR THAT AND JUST SAY THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHANNEL
FOUR FOR BRINGING THIS FORWARD .
>> SUPERVISOR CHEN THANK YOU FOR SUPERVISOR CHEN'S
LEADERSHIP AND I WOULD LIKE TO ADD MYSELF TO THIS PIECE TWO
ITEMS 18 AS A CO-SPONSOR. THANK YOU.
>> SUPERVISOR FIELDER THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHAN FOR YOUR
LEADERSHIP ON THIS AND PLEASE JOIN ME AS A CO-SPONSOR FOR
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD. >> LET'S BE HONEST CO-SPONSOR
AS WELL NOTED AND PLEASE ADD ME AND AND WITH THAT MADAM CLERK
OH OH. >> SUPERVISOR SHERYL SORRY.
>> I WAS TRYING TO GET YOUR ATTENTION THERE.
YES. >> SAME NOTED.
THANK YOU. SEEMS IS OKAY GOING ONCE OR
TWICE ALL RIGHT. I THINK WITH THAT WE CAN TAKE
ITEM 20. SAME HOUSE AND THAT'S NOT THAT
I'M 20 ITEMS 18 SAME HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION ADOPTED AND MADAM CLERK DO WE HAVE ANY IMPERATIVE
AGENDA ITEMS? >> THERE ARE NONE TO REPORT.
MR. PRESIDENT, WOULD YOU PLEASE READ THE IN MEMORIAM
YESTERDAY'S MEETING WILL BE ADJOURNED IN MEMORY OF THE
FOLLOWING BELOVED INDIVIDUAL. ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR MELGAR
FOR THE LATE MR. JAKE SIG ON BEHALF OF PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN
FOR THE LATE MR. IRA SANDLER AND MR. JEFF LITTLEFIELD.
THANK YOU MADAM CLERK. I THINK THAT BRINGS US TO THE
END OF OUR AGENDA DO WE HAVE ANY FURTHER BUSINESS BEFORE US
TODAY? >> THAT CONCLUDES OUR BUSINESS
FOR TODAY. >> WE ARE ADJOURNED.
>> OH ASAPH GOV TV SAN FRANCISCO GOVERNMENT TELEVISION